<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Austin - Code for America Brigade - Austin, Texas</title>
    <description>Open Austin is a volunteer citizen brigade advocating for open government, open data, and civic application development since 2009. We are an official brigade affiliated with the nonprofit Code for America which believes government can work for the people, by the people in the 21st century. Open Austin is focused on the needs of our own community and we use design, technology, and open data to improve the quality of life in our city.</description>
    <link>http://open-austin.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://open-austin.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 12:06:53 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 12:06:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>May Open Gov &amp; Civic Tech Meetup Recap - Texas Water Planning App by TNRIS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For Open Austin’s May Open Gov &amp;amp; Civic Tech Meetup, we hosted two presentations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;texas-water-plan-interactive-app--api&quot;&gt;2017 Texas Water Plan Interactive App &amp;amp; API&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The featured presentation was led by James Seppi (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/MaptimeATX/&quot;&gt;Maptime ATX&lt;/a&gt;) &amp;amp; Matt Nelson, Director of Water Planning at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twdb.texas.gov/&quot;&gt;Texas Water Development Board&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt &amp;amp; James shared:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basics of how Texas does its water planning, including important terminology&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Short demo/how to navigate and interpret the 2017 State Water Plan application&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Summary of API endpoints in the 2017 State Water Plan application&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technology behind the application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1bbrVWdT2R6N3qOT6PfIKQUB5myycgszWVg8MJmJg7PI/edit#slide=id.p&quot;&gt;Here is a link to their presentation&lt;/a&gt;.
Here is a link to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://2017.texasstatewaterplan.org/&quot;&gt;2017 Water Plan App&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://2017.texasstatewaterplan.org/api/v1&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;, and their &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TNRIS/iswp2017&quot;&gt;Github repo&lt;/a&gt; with the open-source code.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;At the always interesting &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;@openaustin&lt;/a&gt; hearing about water resources as well as city performance measurement. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/YPa3kIE0pd&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/YPa3kIE0pd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; david holmes (@texasdnc) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/texasdnc/status/732367709728428032&quot;&gt;May 17, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ditching-pdfs-for-open-data-at-the-city-opm&quot;&gt;Ditching PDFs for Open Data at the City OPM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a bonus presentation, Kimberly Springer-Olivares, Chief Performance Officer at the City of Austin’s newly created Office of Performance Management gave a quick introduction to the new office and previewed plans to ditch PDF reports and make it easier for Austin residents to see how the City is performing using open data and visualizations via new Socrata products offered within data.austintexas.gov.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kim discussed how part of their goal is to ask the questions: Why do departments do the things that they do? How does their budget support those goals? One of the goals of her office is to transform the long Annual Budget Perform Report PDFs (&lt;a href=&quot;https://assets.austintexas.gov/budget/13-14/downloads/2013-14_Austin_Annual_Performance_Report_web.pdf&quot;&gt;like this one for 2013-14 that is 216 pages long&lt;/a&gt;), into more digestable and accessible &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/stories/s/mfnw-2iaf&quot;&gt;“stories” like this one hosted on the city’s data portal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/documents/OPM_OpenAustin.pdf&quot;&gt;Here is a link to the Office of Performance Management slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Kim Springer-Olivares geeks out with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;@openaustin&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/data?src=hash&quot;&gt;#data&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/openperformance?src=hash&quot;&gt;#openperformance&lt;/a&gt; for better government &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/austintexasgov&quot;&gt;@austintexasgov&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/maTQws87N5&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/maTQws87N5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jill Goodman (@cafejillio) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cafejillio/status/732377364332568576&quot;&gt;May 17, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1czm4VlA9376cmfobLgrxLLwA01_NXFBKs34FcDVrn_I/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Open Austin event intro slides with announcements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue the conversation by following us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and joining our community on &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;.
RSVP for our next event on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; and like us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; to stay up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/05/28/may-open-gov-civic-tech-meetup-recap</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/05/28/may-open-gov-civic-tech-meetup-recap</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My day as a UXer at the Designing for Civic Solutions Workshop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a UX Design student in my final semester at ACC, I was thrilled to have the opportunity to attend the Open Austin’s Designing for Civic Solutions Workshop. It was held at the Little Walnut Creek Branch, Austin Public Library located near the Rundberg and North Lamar intersection. Snacks, refreshments, and lunch were provided to keep us well-fueled for the day’s human-centered design activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning started with an introduction by Mateo Clarke and Victoria O’Dell of Open Austin. Next we learned about the Rundberg community, and issues the area faces from Daniela Nuñez, Co-Vice President of the Georgian Acres Neighborhood Association. The human-centered design portion of the workshop was kicked off by Eric Boggs, AC4D alumni, followed by Bhavini Patel, Laura Galos, James Lewis, and Samara Watkiss. Each took turns introducing the room to a different phase of the process we’d utilize for the duration of the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we moved into the &lt;strong&gt;Research&lt;/strong&gt; phase, participants broke up into small teams to choose what they would focus on for the day. I teamed with Lora Rowan and Kayla Kennett to focus on &lt;strong&gt;“what it feels like to be a bicyclist or pedestrian crossing the intersection at North Lamar and Rundberg”&lt;/strong&gt;, one of the most dangerous intersections in the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We collaborated to come up with open-ended questions, and headed out into the field on foot to ask area residents our questions with the goals of gaining empathy and insights. We successfully interviewed a few Austin residents, although we ran into language barriers with a couple of other potential interviewees. We took turns serving as the facilitator, notetaker, and photographer. Soon the heat of the afternoon kicked in, and we headed back to the Library for a break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ellen-Contextal-observation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ladies crossing N Lamar in the middle of the street&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Contextual observation - These ladies crossed N Lamar in the middle of the street and seemed very calm. They were standing in the street waiting to cross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the our lunch break concluded, we moved into the &lt;strong&gt;Synthesis&lt;/strong&gt; phase of the workshop. We were led through a series of exercises where we examined what our interviewees shared with our team, and discovered themes and insights. This is the phase where the post-its and scissors were put into heavy use, as we collaborated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ellen-mentor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4 participants organize sticky notes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Eric Boggs mentoring, me (left), Lora (middle), Kayla (right)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;strong&gt;Ideation&lt;/strong&gt; phase we were encouraged to generate many ideas without censorship in our teams. During this phase we engaged each team member, and openly encouraged the sharing of ideas and opinions. Then we used creative downselection, to identify ideas based on criteria appropriate to the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we moved into &lt;strong&gt;Storyboarding as a Prototyping tool&lt;/strong&gt;. Each team member created their own storyboard during this phase. We brought our individual design vision to life using a concise and focused approach to introducing the people in our story, showing the problem, the solution, and the result. We also learned some pretty nifty shortcuts to expressing emotion with facial expressions, that help the viewer understand the emotions tied to the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ellen-storyboard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ellen&#39;s story board&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This was my storyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I thoroughly enjoyed the workshop, and hope that some of the ideas from attendees might solve the issue of mobility in Austin. It was incredible getting out in the field to conduct research, and listen to Austinites share their stories. Learning and applying AC4D alumni’s human-centered design process was also quite rewarding in many ways.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/05/04/my-day-as-a-uxer-designing-for-civic-solutions</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/05/04/my-day-as-a-uxer-designing-for-civic-solutions</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>April Open Gov &amp; Civic Tech Meetup Recap - Ann Armstrong &amp; Austin&#39;s Atlas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For Open Austin’s April Open Gov &amp;amp; Civic Tech Meetup, Ann Armstrong was invited to speak about her collaborative project, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.austinsatlas.com/&quot;&gt;Austin’s Atlas&lt;/a&gt;, which straddles the intersection of art, cartography, and urban history. Ann is an architect, welder, and artist, living in Austin for 10 years having moved from San Francisco, California for graduate school at the University of Texas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;austins-atlas-origin&quot;&gt;Austin’s Atlas Origin&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Ann first moved to Austin she felt disconnected from her surroundings. She starting taking walks, not to get anywhere, but to explore a neighborhood. At first, she was frustrated with the city’s poor walkability compared to San Francisco. Austin is not as dense, her walks were less stimulating, and there was not as much street art. But, as she kept walking, she fell more and more in love with Austin, its nooks and crannies, and “urban oddities.” Not before long, Ann realized that her favorites waypoints were rapidly disappearing due to new construction, weather, or other unexplained occurrences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve never lived in a city that was growing so rapidly.” Said Ann, “I’m an architect. I understand that the city has to grow. But it feels like it’s on steroids.” Her exploration of the growing city soon lead to documentation. “My first attempt at documenting Austin was all about the sidewalks” Armstrong continued. Ann documented the sidewalks for 2 years, which evolved into documenting public art. Then she started making and collecting maps. “The first map I made myself was about urban oddities. It was the first map I made to be used by other people.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these efforts were fueled by the idea of making the city more knowable. Ann said she was trying to, “expand on the existing sense of place by revealing things about it and also understanding how other people see the city.” She pushed the idea further and started to host walks and workshops around different themes, and by collaborating with other mapmakers and urban explorers like Emma Schmidt and Angela Hanson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-does-austins-atlas-add-new-maps&quot;&gt;How does Austin’s Atlas add new maps?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The artifacts of Ann’s walks, workshops, collaborations and exchanges became the foundation for Austin’s Atlas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her first solution for collecting more maps was an exchange system. “I give you a map, you give me map.” It was a simple concept that helped grow the collection. However, Ann knew that in order to increase the amount of maps she collected she would have to create more opportunity for exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This inspired her to build a cart and show up to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/540975332670526/&quot;&gt;Park(ing) Day 2014&lt;/a&gt; to meet people where they were. She gave out supplies and asked people to draw maps. During an &lt;a href=&quot;http://east.bigmedium.org/&quot;&gt;East Austin Studio Tour (E.A.S.T)&lt;/a&gt; event she set up a “map drive” and collected 120+ drawn maps from people of various backgrounds over the course of 2 weekends in an art studio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;During an East Austin studio tour Ann set up a map drive and collected over 120 maps over 2 weekends. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/sZTKX4NnMB&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/sZTKX4NnMB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/722227520364421120&quot;&gt;April 19, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a process! It’s hard to collect maps from people.” The less than conventional ask has proven to be slow and involved. She said she doesn’t give people a ton of directions for map making but has the request that they title it. Interpretation often depends on how the map maker frames the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;map-making-exercise&quot;&gt;Map Making Exercise&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conclude the presentation, Ann handed out sheets of paper with a short questionnaire, a small map of Austin, and an empty space for sketching. She invited Open Austinites to answer some questions about their residence and commute then to mark roughly where they live on the map. Lastly, participants were to draw the scene they see out of a window they look out of the most at their home. Participants said the process was therapeutic. All of the images told a story unique story about disparate residential scenes in Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Open Austinites work on their own maps. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/J9XZVYMZuj&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/J9XZVYMZuj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/722234979707592705&quot;&gt;April 19, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;We maaaaappped! &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/TlFlkqChaS&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/TlFlkqChaS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Amalie Barras (@AmalieBarras) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AmalieBarras/status/722234618116595713&quot;&gt;April 19, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a link to a &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/documents/OA_Austin_Atlas_Scans.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF with the maps&lt;/a&gt; that Open Austinites made for Austin’s Atlas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann shared her &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/documents/April_18_Austins_Atlas_presentation.pdf&quot;&gt;presentation slides here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about her work, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://ann-made.org/&quot;&gt;Ann Armstrong’s personal site&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.austinsatlas.com/&quot;&gt;view the Austin’s Atlas site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/157dhPuRQNa4vpyp1YjCY8ao7tWcxs9ma7lQDeIHENpQ/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Open Austin’s introduction slides for the Meetup are linked here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue the conversation by following us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and joining our community on &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;.
RSVP for our next event on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; and like us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; to stay up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/04/24/open-gov-civic-tech-austin-atlas-recap</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/04/24/open-gov-civic-tech-austin-atlas-recap</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Press Release - Open Austin Collaborates with AC4D Alumni to Host Workshop</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;collaboration-seeks-to-bring-design-methodology-to-civic-tech-in-austin&quot;&gt;Collaboration seeks to bring design methodology to civic tech in Austin&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Austin, TX:&lt;/strong&gt; Open Austin, a volunteer-driven civic tech organization, will host a one-day workshop on Saturday, April 23rd. The workshop is a day of collaboration between Open Austin and &lt;a href=&quot;ac4d.com&quot;&gt;Austin Center for Design (AC4D)&lt;/a&gt; alumni to teach community members how human-centered design improves social impact when working on civic projects. The workshop is being held at Little Walnut Creek Library at 835 West Rundberg Lane. The event is free and open to the public and attendees must &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/designing-for-civic-solutions-workshop-tickets-24534044989&quot;&gt;register via Eventbrite&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme of the workshop is designing for “Mobility in Austin”. The focus will be on transportation issues in the area. “As mobility discussions are happening all over the city, Open Austin presents a unique model for working collaboratively to solve a community’s pressing mobility challenges,” said Daniela Nuñez, Co-Vice President of the Georgian Acres Neighborhood Association. Nuñez will be giving a short presentation to workshop attendees about the the history of the area and the issues that are most prominent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I believe events like this are important steps towards future collaboration between community leaders, designers, technologists, and interested citizens.” said Eric Boggs, AC4D Alumni Coordinator and host facilitator. “If we’re going to do anything truly innovative or useful beyond the status quo to address our civic issues, it will take a shared understanding of what problem needs solving and for whom. Human Centered Design can provide that framework.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through this collaboration the Open Austin hopes attendees will contribute research and ideas to existing issues of mobility in Austin. Furthermore, the workshop will give attendees the opportunity to learn human-centered design research methodologies, and empower attendees with new skills and knowledge to apply to current and future projects. Donations from local organizations Austin CityUp, HubCiti, Austin B-Cycle, USAA, and IBM Design helped make this event possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Open Austin:&lt;/strong&gt; Open Austin, is a volunteer citizen brigade advocating for open government, open data, and civic application development since 2009. They are an official brigade affiliated with the nonprofit Code for America, which believes government can work for the people, by the people in the 21st century. Open Austin is focused on the needs of the community and uses design, technology, and open data to advocate for improved quality of life in Austin, Texas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;###&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/04/18/open-austin-collaborates-with-ac4d-alumni-to-host-workshop</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/04/18/open-austin-collaborates-with-ac4d-alumni-to-host-workshop</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Designing for Civic Solutions Workshop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Sat, April 23, 2016
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 10:00 am – 4:45 pm
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Little Walnut Creek Branch, Austin Public Library - 835 West Rundberg Lane, Austin, TX 78758  (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/dir/30.2304666,-97.7374643/30.3636444,-97.6983433/@30.2861351,-97.7667604,12z/data=!4m4!4m3!1m1!4e1!1m0&quot;&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/designing-for-civic-solutions-workshop-tickets-24534044989&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REGISTER NOW&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Designing for Civic Solutions&lt;/strong&gt; is a one-day workshop and collaboration between Open Austin and Austin Center for Design (AC4D) alumni to teach community members how to use a human-centered design process to focus on social impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workshop attendees will engage in ethnographic research, synthesis, and rapid ideation centered on the theme of “mobility in Austin”. They will be empowered to use these skills to research, design, and prototype other civic tech and social good projects important to them and their surrounding communities. To learn this process they will form small groups focusing on different aspects of mobility in Austin around the Rundberg neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event will be free and open to the public. No design or development skills are necessary to attend this workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;goals-for-this-workshop&quot;&gt;Goals for this workshop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon completion of the workshop, Participants will learn how to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contribute their research and ideas to the existing pressing issue of mobility in Austin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conduct human-centered research around the theme of mobility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Translate their research into meaningful insights&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practice ideation methods based on their insights from the field&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use storyboarding as a way to prototype ideas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apply this process and these skills to future projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;workshop-facilitators&quot;&gt;Workshop Facilitators&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eric Boggs&lt;/strong&gt; is an interaction designer at Blackboard in Austin, TX, focused on designing mobile applications for students.  He believes in the power of design to help address large scale social issues, and has completed a variety of research projects on student loan debt, family caregiving, and healthy shopping to inform product and service innovation.  Eric graduated from the Austin Center for Design in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bhavini Patel&lt;/strong&gt; is a freelance UX Experience Researcher &amp;amp; Interaction Designer.  Bhavini has worked in collaboration with Projekt202, Chaotic Moon Studios, Wondros, Zogotech and Saatchi and Saatchi.  She is a graduate of Austin Center for Design and splits her time between Los Angeles and Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laura Galos&lt;/strong&gt; is a design researcher at IBM in Austin, Texas. Her past projects include research in aging and family dynamics, service design, and ad technology. She is a 2015 graduate of Austin Center for Design with certification in Interaction Design and Social Entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James Lewis&lt;/strong&gt; is a curious, passionate interaction designer who likes to embrace the ambiguity of complex problems, creating clear solutions for both the end user and client. He previously worked to change hearts and minds in the political advocacy and non profit arenas. Now he works as a user experience designer at IBM designing products for developers who work with big data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samara Watkiss&lt;/strong&gt; arrived at interaction design as a profession and calling by pursuing the most inspiring aspects of her work as a set designer, pedal-powered machine builder, graphic designer and refugee-liaison and asking how they all connected. After several years of working as an Interaction in Boston, she moved to Austin, TX to complete a degree in Interaction Design and Social Entrepreneurship at the Austin Center for Design. She now leads a human-centered design initiative for a local cyber security company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;this-event-is-conducted-under-the-open-austin-code-of-conduct&quot;&gt;This event is conducted under the Open Austin Code of Conduct&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/about/code-of-conduct&quot;&gt;http://www.open-austin.org/about/code-of-conduct
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;this-event-is-made-possible-by-generous-donations-from&quot;&gt;This event is made possible by generous donations from:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/usaa.png&quot; alt=&quot;USAA Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/austin-cityup.png&quot; alt=&quot;Austin CityUp Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hubciti.png&quot; alt=&quot;HubCiti Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/austin-b-cycle.png&quot; alt=&quot;Austin B-Cycle Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ibm-design.png&quot; alt=&quot;IBM Design Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Presented by 
&lt;br /&gt;Open Austin in Collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ac4d.com/&quot;&gt;Austin Center for Design&lt;/a&gt; Alumni&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/04/12/designing-for-civic-solutions-workshop</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/04/12/designing-for-civic-solutions-workshop</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>City of Austin Open Data Initiative April Meetup Recap</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, April 6th, the City of Austin Open Data Initiative Team hosted an educational meetup and update at the City Council Chambers of City Hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Data Initiative (ODI) is moving progress forward internally through a “sprint” model, where each sprint represents a 90-day time frame. The current sprint, ODI sprint 2.1 began on February 16th and will end on May 16th, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an overview of objectives of the current ODI sprint, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityofaustin.github.io/open-data-docs/projects/sprint_2_1/&quot;&gt;http://sprint.opendata.rocks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-data-initiative-sprint-21-updates&quot;&gt;Open Data Initiative Sprint 2.1 Updates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four of the six captains that serve as leads on the sprint objectives presented updates on the progress towards their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brad McCarty&lt;/strong&gt;, captain of inventory team shared that they are trying to create a process for maintaining the city wide inventory of datasets. They are looking at examples from New York and San Francisco of how they manage their data inventories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marbenn Cayetano&lt;/strong&gt;, captains the team working to update the documentation of Austin’s open data assets on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://us-city.census.okfn.org/&quot;&gt;US Open Data Census website&lt;/a&gt;. The team is currently breaking up the census into sections and assigning out tasks. So far, they have submitted one update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hailey Pate&lt;/strong&gt;, gave an update that the sprint definition document is available to the public at &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityofaustin.github.io/open-data-docs/projects/sprint_2_1/&quot;&gt;http://sprint.opendata.rocks&lt;/a&gt;. She also gave an update on the “Request a Dataset” Workflow. Her team is deciding what do they want the experience for requesting, voting, and filtering dataset request to be like. They met with CoA Enterprise Architect Rob Byrd to design a workflow that is software platform agnostic. By the end of the project, the team hopes to have to built a solution in Github, or at least have requirements to give to a vendor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Janette Milan&lt;/strong&gt; leads the team working on Open Data Portal Homepage redesign. They recently opened an &lt;a href=&quot;https://austintexas-data.demo.socrata.com/&quot;&gt;alpha preview&lt;/a&gt; of the new landing page design &lt;em&gt;(warning: this demo link is liable to break in the near future)&lt;/em&gt;. Janette’s team also published a &lt;a href=&quot;https://cityofaustin.typeform.com/to/xYOhoz&quot;&gt;user survey&lt;/a&gt; to collect feedback from the community. They will be providing a report to the Open Government Governing Board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/alpha-preview-socrata.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of the new data portal landing page&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of May, there will be another ODI Meetup with presentations on the outcomes of the sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;guest-speakers&quot;&gt;Guest Speakers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the City of Austin team updates, the majority of the meetup was dedicated to two separate presentations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;Stuart Gano&lt;/strong&gt;, a solutions architect at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://socrata.com&quot;&gt;Socrata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; spoke about open data trends he’s seeing across the country. The key insight I took away from Stuart’s presentation is that open government data started with uncontroversial topics, like building permits, or service requests by district. Governments would avoid more touchy topics like police data incident responses and officer involved shootings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But within the last year, police data has been a driving force behind open data publication across the country. This data is what citizens are asking for. Additionally, these topics are receiving national attention, for example the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2015/10/27/police-data-initiative-5-month-update&quot;&gt;White House Police Data Initiative&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a link to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/dataset/Officer-Involved-Shootings/xsje-n5tj&quot;&gt;Austin Police Departments’s Office Involved Shootings dataset&lt;/a&gt;, which only went live towards the end of last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unmil.ischool.utexas.edu/&quot;&gt;Professor Unmil Karadkar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;UT’s School of Information&lt;/strong&gt; gave a presentation on basics of data visualization, what is the difference between dynamic dashboards and curated infographics, and what types of visualizations are most effective for different datasets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep up with our future events and join our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;Meetup group to RSVP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also feel free to check out our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/events&quot;&gt;calendar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ready to start working with us? Join us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; now or check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/project-ideas&quot;&gt;Github Idea repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/04/11/coa-odi-april-meetup-recap</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/04/11/coa-odi-april-meetup-recap</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Austin City Council Agendas Become Open Data</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Beginning in January 2016, the Austin City Council has been 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/Government/Austin-City-Council-Agenda-Items/es7e-878h&quot;&gt;publishing the agenda items from its weekly meetings&lt;/a&gt; 
on the city data portal at &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/&quot;&gt;data.austintexas.gov&lt;/a&gt;, in a structured format with computer-readable dates,
meeting types, and other details. This new resource was a much-appreciated response to several Open Austin project teams
who were interested in creating new ways for residents to learn about the city council’s activities, but who discovered that
data collection involved a prohibitively difficult process of scraping text from PDF files stored in 
a &lt;a href=&quot;http://austintexas.gov/department/city-council/council-meetings&quot;&gt;confusing directory structure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;https://makerbase.co/p/uwt239/atxcouncilconn&quot;&gt;an attempt in 2015&lt;/a&gt; to create an 
agenda item notification system called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/council-connect&quot;&gt;ATX Council Connect&lt;/a&gt; had to be abandoned at 
the prototype phase, Open Austin members made it a priority in 
our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/advocacy/documents/OpenAustinAdvocacyAgenda2016.pdf&quot;&gt;2016 Advocacy Agenda&lt;/a&gt; to ask the city to 
release data about the council’s activities in a more useable format. Mateo Clarke and Shellee O’Brien, a leader of the original
Council Connect project, used the city’s interest in soliciting bids for a new agenda management system as an opportunity to
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1FOLuCR6kRRTLQD5dyJCuIquRkEoaGi0aqAVlBFwVuPY/&quot;&gt;draft a new position paper and bring it to the city&lt;/a&gt;,
asking the city to treat the agendas as a public resource, and to make them reuseable and accessible in bulk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now there are at least two teams within Open Austin interested in finding uses for the new city council data: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/project-ideas/issues/36&quot;&gt;one project to geocode 
agenda items&lt;/a&gt; and display them on a Google map for an easy overview, and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/lobbying-in-austin&quot;&gt;another project to integrate the agendas dataset&lt;/a&gt; with the city’s separate &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/dataset/Lobbyists/bqav-9x6a&quot;&gt;lobbyist&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/Government/Campaign-Finance-Data-Transaction-Detail-Dataset/g4yx-aw9r&quot;&gt;campaign finance&lt;/a&gt; datasets. When the city chose the solution of publishing the agenda items on data.austintexas.gov, these teams were thrilled and energized 
to find out they were going to be saved the effort of scraping and parsing the text themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/project-ideas/issues/36&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/agendaGithubComment.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;GitHub comment: &amp;quot;davemcphee commented 16 days ago: * looks at 160 lines of python parser code, eye twitches *&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get involved, you can &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;join the discussion on Open Austin’s Slack board&lt;/a&gt;, and if you have a new idea about how to
use the city council’s data, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/project-ideas&quot;&gt;share it on our Ideas page on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/04/02/austin-city-council-agendas-become-open-data</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/04/02/austin-city-council-agendas-become-open-data</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>March Open Gov &amp; Civic Tech Meetup Recap - APD Body Cameras</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;body-cams-in-austin&quot;&gt;Body Cams in Austin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our March Open Gov &amp;amp; Civic Tech Meetup, we invited Kathy Mitchell, from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://txepc.org/&quot;&gt;Texas Electronic Privacy Coalition&lt;/a&gt;, to give a presentation on Police Body Cameras and the technology, laws, and advocacy opportunities surrounding their implementation at the Austin Police Department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/documents/Austin_Body_Cam.pdf&quot;&gt;Here are the slides that Kathy provided.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Kathy Mitchell presenting to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;@openaustin&lt;/a&gt; on Austin police body cam policy. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EFFaustin&quot;&gt;@EFFaustin&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/9sVERhbl44&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/9sVERhbl44&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; luqmaan (@luqmonster) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/luqmonster/status/712115221783908357&quot;&gt;March 22, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key point of Kathy’s presentation was that simply having body cams on police officers does not automatically equal transparency. The current state law that provides funding and the legal framework for body cams incentivizes law enforcement agencies to adopt body cameras, but to not make the data public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An innovative idea is to create an opt-in option for citizens that become the subject of police body cam recordings. This would allow the public to access those recordings with the consent of the recorded subject who has either had a really poor experience with the police, a really good interaction, or something in between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Open Austin members discuss what they would want in police body cam policy. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ATX?src=hash&quot;&gt;#ATX&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/OpenGov?src=hash&quot;&gt;#OpenGov&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/1A9Hrf7ggW&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/1A9Hrf7ggW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/712082658218520576&quot;&gt;March 22, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kathy asked Open Austin members what they would like to see in a Body Cam Open Data Policy. Members recognized that release of all camera footage would be troubling for privacy reasons, but metadata like geospatial information and length of recordings could be a valuable analysis tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;particpate-in-upcoming-body-cam-actions&quot;&gt;Particpate in upcoming body cam actions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get involved with this issue, we encourage you to sign up for our body cam listserv and/or volunteer for a working group by filling out this form.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/forms/QN5vZejo2P&quot;&gt;http://goo.gl/forms/QN5vZejo2P&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-resources&quot;&gt;More Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Legislation authorizing body cams and setting the legal framework for Texas: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capitol.state.tx.us/tlodocs/84R/billtext/html/SB00158F.htm&quot;&gt;84(R) SB 158&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.austintexas.gov/APDbodycam&quot;&gt;City of Austin APD Bodycam page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;City of Austin body cam vendor &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.austintexas.gov/financeonline/vendor_connection/solicitation/solicitation_details.cfm?sid=110270&quot;&gt;RFP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://austintexas.gov/sites/default/files/files/Police/APD_Policy_2015-2_Issued_5-1-2015-updated.pdf&quot;&gt;Current body cam policy&lt;/a&gt; to be replaced by one that addresses key issues: (Go to policy 303 at page 125.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-watch/wp/2016/02/05/a-new-report-shows-the-limits-of-police-body-cameras/&quot;&gt;Washington Post: A new report shows the limits of police body cameras&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brennancenter.org/analysis/police-body-camera-policies-privacy-and-first-amendment-protections&quot;&gt;Brennan Center for Justice: Police Body Camera Policies: Privacy and First Amendment Protections&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep up with our future events and join our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;Meetup group to RSVP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also feel free to check out our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/events&quot;&gt;calendar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ready to start working with us? Join us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; now or check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/project-ideas&quot;&gt;Github Idea repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/03/29/open-gov-civic-tech-bodycam-recap</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/03/29/open-gov-civic-tech-bodycam-recap</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CodeAcross Austin 2016 Recap</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past Saturday, March 5, 2015, Open Austin had it’s 6th annual CodeAcross Austin event. This national day of action aligns with International Open Data Day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeforamerica.org/events/codeacross-2016/&quot;&gt;CodeAcross&lt;/a&gt; is the first major event of the year that Open Austin organizes as a volunteer brigade affiliated with Code for America. It is a part of a series of events in collaboration with the City of Austin and St. Edward’s leading up to ATX Hack For Change (June 3-5). The purpose of Code Across Austin this year was to identify and frame challenges in Austin that can be solved using technology, data, design and the diverse skills and knowledge of volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning kicked off at 10:00 am with introductory remarks from Mateo Clarke &amp;amp; Victoria O’Dell of Open Austin. Then, visiting from San Francisco, Monique Baena-Tan, Brigade Program Coordinator from Code for America, spoke about the international reach of the brigade program. The morning presentations ended with Kerry O’Connor, Chief Innovation Officer for the City of Austin sharing inspiring words about the importance of civic hacking events like CodeAcross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/codeacross-2016-pano.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pano view of the crowd during morning presentations&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Favorite quote from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/codeacrossatx?src=hash&quot;&gt;#codeacrossatx&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;Disruption will come to government either as an opportunity or a threat.&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kerry_atx&quot;&gt;@kerry_atx&lt;/a&gt; ⚡️&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;@openaustin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Mateo Clarke (@MateoClarke) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MateoClarke/status/706265412795658240&quot;&gt;March 5, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quote from Kerry O’Connor’s presentation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cfa-slide.png&quot; alt=&quot;Description of Code for America from slidedeck.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1INnwL4NGuiIFqIl_N_eLJrxKmhxT_hdULH9uCFW7zTw/edit#slide=id.g11c404532b_4_63&quot;&gt;View Monique’s presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of day was broken into group activities arranged around 8 themes and their relation to the city of Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Health and Human services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Public Safety &amp;amp; Justice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Economic Development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Communication and Engagement&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transportation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Broadband and Digital Opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sustainability&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Planning and Land Use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants with varying backgrounds brainstormed on challenges the city faces and worked on actionable steps that could be taken to tackle them. By the end of the morning, groups focused on each theme had drafted at least three “How might we..” challenge statements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/how-might-we.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A participant add a sticky to a how might we challenge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second half of the day focused on turning the challenge statements into potential solutions with an actionable plan. Charles Purma, project manager for the City of Austin, presented the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/civic-tech-canvas/&quot;&gt;“Civic Tech Canvas”&lt;/a&gt; that groups used to plan out a solution to their chosen challenge statements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hack-canvas.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two ladies add post it notes to their hack canvas&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With contributions from around 60 participants of different backgrounds, ages, and professions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/project-ideas/issues?q=is%3Aopen+is%3Aissue+label%3ACodeAcross2016&quot;&gt;11 different project ideas&lt;/a&gt; were presented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code Across is over but the ideas sharing and collaboration that occurred will allow the Austin community and Open Austin to continue to do open source civic tech and design work for the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1aWNB5wWr9ZIjwvMNEZR2uoGJcK9zDKuFw0_B1JIhFBk/edit#slide=id.g11c5e340a8_0_17&quot;&gt;our deck&lt;/a&gt; from event and check out tweets from the event at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=codeacrossatx&amp;amp;src=typd&amp;amp;lang=en&quot;&gt;#codeacrossatx&lt;/a&gt;
Check out our event &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.962504890492340.1073741830.412390968837071&amp;amp;type=1&amp;amp;l=d32fcb860f&quot;&gt;photo album&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Missed out on this year’s CodeAcross? Come out to our next event.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/events/228334335/&quot;&gt;Civic Hack Saturday&lt;/a&gt; is on March 19th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the Open Austin community on Slack: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Get an invite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
RSVP for our future events on Meetup: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Follow us on Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Follow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;amp; Like us on Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Like&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/03/10/codeacross-austin-2016-recap</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/03/10/codeacross-austin-2016-recap</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SXSW 2016 Open Data &amp; Civic Tech Events</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;SXSW Interactive takes place in Austin during March 10-15 this year. It will feature hundreds of panels, workshops, and parties, and even a visit from President Obama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, combing through all the official and unofficial events while keeping track of RSVPs can be super daunting, so we decided to help our our Open Data &amp;amp; Civic Tech friends with a curated list of relevant events to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, this list features 38 events pertaining to Open Data, Civic Technology, Policy, and SmartCities. At this time, most of the events on this list are official events, but we encourage you to &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#102;&amp;#111;&amp;#064;&amp;#111;&amp;#112;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#045;&amp;#097;&amp;#117;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#046;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#103;&quot;&gt;shoot us an email&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;tweet us&lt;/a&gt; if you have anything else to add.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you can’t make it to SXSW, we hope we’ll see you at our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/events/228334335/&quot;&gt;next event&lt;/a&gt; on March 19th at Urban Co-Lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VnBJafxvbeIkGemBpu_l3UNt7JRV8u5KNnG3tJGpESQ/edit#gid=0&quot;&gt;View the Google Doc here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few highlights, in chronological order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ibm-design-hive-at-sxsw&quot;&gt;IBM Design Hive at SXSW&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Friday, March 11, All Day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Hotel Van Zandt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_OE04783&quot;&gt;Official SXSW Event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 4PM, Russ Unger of 18F will present. Aside from being friends of Code for America and Open Austin, &lt;em&gt;“18F is a civic consultancy for the government, inside the government, enabling agencies to rapidly deploy tools and services that are easy to operate, cost efficient, and reusable.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;voter-technology-a-reimagined-future&quot;&gt;Voter Technology: A Reimagined Future&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Friday, March 11, 9:30 AM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Old School Bar, 401 E 6th St&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP58068&quot;&gt;Official SXSW Event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Aging voting technology means upcoming elections are more likely than ever to result in inaccurate ballots or in voters being unable to cast a ballot at all. This group of panelists is unafraid to both sound the alarm bells and inspire us all about what is at stake for the 2016 presidential election, what stands in the way of updated voter technology, and what the future of the voter experience could look like given the right tools.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dell-policy-hack&quot;&gt;Dell Policy Hack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Saturday, March 12, 6:00 PM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;115 San Jacinto Austin, TX&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;No Badge Required&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://dell-policy-hack.splashthat.com/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Join Dell for an interactive hack-a-thon that tasks teams of policymakers, entrepreneurs, venture capitalists and students, along with a “coach”, to design solutions to policy challenges faced by entrepreneurs running growing businesses. The goal is to share the winning solution with the next president, recommending he or she implement them in their first 100 days in office.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;civic-tech-hackers-and-advocates-meet-up&quot;&gt;Civic Tech Hackers and Advocates Meet Up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Monday, March 14th, 11 AM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;JW Marriott Room 209&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP55660&quot;&gt;Official SXSW Event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you don’t know already, Open Austin is hosting an official SXSW meetup to bring civic advocates, hackers, and supporters from all over together to share wins and roadblocks, and discuss ideas to take home.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/03/07/sxsw-2016-events</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/03/07/sxsw-2016-events</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
