<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Austin - Code for America Brigade - Austin, Texas</title>
    <description>Open Austin is a volunteer citizen brigade advocating for open government, open data, and civic application development since 2009. We are an official brigade affiliated with the nonprofit Code for America which believes government can work for the people, by the people in the 21st century. Open Austin is focused on the needs of our own community and we use design, technology, and open data to improve the quality of life in our city.</description>
    <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 22:35:12 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 22:35:12 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>City Releases Some Requested Data about Lobbyists and City Council</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, Austin City Clerk Jannette Goodall and other city officials met with Open Austin and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.austintech.org/&quot;&gt;Austin Tech Alliance&lt;/a&gt; about two datasets requested in the joint OA/ATA &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1nJZ1y4YPiNpuHpoduCIPpF-oF_qOPp8UmDswiEbN-Ts/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;2018 advocacy agenda&lt;/a&gt;: lobbyist activity reports and city council meeting records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lobbyist-activity-reports&quot;&gt;Lobbyist Activity Reports&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, several Open Austin members have made efforts to create research tools about lobbying, but they found it difficult because few of the records were available in a form that was easy for computers to read, and even the information that was being posted was sometimes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.open-austin.org/blog/2017/10/05/changes-in-access-to-Austins-local-legislative-data&quot;&gt;unexpectedly removed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the city clerk’s office has published &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/browse?q=lobbyist&amp;amp;sortBy=relevance&quot;&gt;several new tables of lobbyist data&lt;/a&gt;, including client names, subject matter of lobbying, expenditures, and compensation. This covers most of the categories of lobbyist information we asked for in our policy agenda. The new datasets include information extracted from the quarterly lobbyist activity reports, but the reports themselves are also published. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.austintexas.gov/department/lobbyists&quot;&gt;2016 lobbyist ordinance&lt;/a&gt; requires significantly more information than under prior law, and some lobbyists even terminated their registrations to avoid having their information disclosed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clerk’s office warned us that the tables on the data portal are views on the city’s database, so if you link them together you won’t exactly get the city database. However, the city plans to post a raw dump of the whole lobbyist database, with an entity relationship diagram and data dictionary. The clerk’s office also expressed interest in ideas about how to present the data better, for instance as stored queries. The clerk’s office doesn’t foresee any more major structural changes to the database unless there are changes to the lobbyist ordinance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the current dataset only goes back about a year, and the older data about lobbist registrations and clients isn’t coming back online. The clerk’s office apparently saved over its old files and thus doesn’t have them anymore. The lobbyist registration documents still exist on paper and anyone can come in and look at them, but even those only go back 2 or 3 years before being destroyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;city-council-agendas&quot;&gt;City Council Agendas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important news for people interested in city council data is probably that the city has finished its transition to a new agenda management system, and it has decided not to deploy the Granicus/Legistar web portal. That means the presentation layer for their website isn’t going to change anytime soon, and any Open Austin projects that depend on data beyond what’s in the data portal will need to scrape the existing website. Because there’s no Legistar web portal, it’s unlikely that anyone will be able to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.councilmatic.org/&quot;&gt;Councilmatic&lt;/a&gt; to interface with the City of Austin system automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the city clerk’s office doesn’t collect or have any data on how the council members vote on agenda items. The office asked last year if the council was interested in starting to collect vote data, and they decided against it, as some council members prefer for their actions to be viewed more as a narrative than as data. For instance, councilmembers wouldn’t want constituents to assume that a vote for an amendment always means they want the ordinance to pass in its amended form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the clerk’s office and the agenda office are separate, the clerk’s office has limited ability to impose a rigid structure on the agenda data it publishes. There are changes and corrections every week, affecting details like public hearing dates, or conditions on board approval of items. Most ordinances and resolutions aren’t even assigned a static ID number until they’re approved, and maintaining the legislative history is difficult for the clerk’s office because there’s no unique identifier for an item. This makes it hard for people trying to work with the council’s data too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, zoning matters do have persistent ID numbers when they come before the council, and the clerk’s office is publishing these &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/City-Government/Current-Agenda-Item-Dataset-2018-/g9iv-xdsg&quot;&gt;on the city data portal&lt;/a&gt;, along with the available structured data on every agenda item. They plan to publish more historical agenda items with zoning ID numbers soon. Users shouldn’t assume the zoning numbers will correspond to the chronological order the zoning matters come before the council. Although we appreciate the city’s efforts to publish more data about the council, Open Austin’s position is still that the council should publish the councilmembers’ votes and should publish ID numbers for every item on its agenda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Continue the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Austin’s advocacy agenda is intended to help get access to data resources based on community members’ demonstrated interest in finding creative ways to use them for the public benefit. Now that the city has released more lobbyist and city council agenda data, it’s a good time to build a project around that data at an Open Austin event like a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/events/247367149/&quot;&gt;Community Action Night&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/events/zfmdhpyxgbkb/&quot;&gt;Civic Hack Saturday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the discussion in the Open Austin community on Slack: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Get an invite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP for our future events on Meetup: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2018/02/25/city-releases-some-requested-data-about-lobbyists-and-city-council</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2018/02/25/city-releases-some-requested-data-about-lobbyists-and-city-council</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Office of Sustainability Offers Guidance for Civic Climate Data</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, representatives of the City of Austin’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.austintexas.gov/department/sustainability&quot;&gt;Office of Sustainability&lt;/a&gt; took time out of their schedules to meet with me, and with David Edmonson of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.austintech.org/&quot;&gt;Austin Tech Alliance&lt;/a&gt;, about the climate data priority in Open Austin’s and Austin Tech Alliance’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1nJZ1y4YPiNpuHpoduCIPpF-oF_qOPp8UmDswiEbN-Ts/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;joint 2018 advocacy agenda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Austin has a goal of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.austintexas.gov/edims/document.cfm?id=234102&quot;&gt;net zero community-wide greenhouse gas emissions by 2050&lt;/a&gt;. The city has the most control over its own emissions from sources like its vehicle fleet, but emissions from city government amount to only about 0.5 percent of the community’s total emissions. The city’s influence over the rest of the community’s emissions is much less direct. In general, the City Council sets an emissions target, and the Office of Sustainability does data collection and analysis to understand current emissions trends. From there, the city’s tools to affect overall emissions include setting the policy for the city-owned &lt;a href=&quot;https://austinenergy.com/ae/&quot;&gt;Austin Energy&lt;/a&gt;, making changes to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.austintexas.gov/department/building-technical-codes&quot;&gt;building code,&lt;/a&gt; and setting transportation policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Austin asked the city to “release the data underlying the Community Climate Plan Progress Updates and the City’s calculated progress on its goal of net-zero community-wide greenhouse gas emissions by 2050.” The purposes of that request were to give residents enough information to evaluate the city’s estimates of the amount of emissions avoided by various categories of efficiency programs, to help evaluate the city’s projections of future emissions, and to identify emissions policy priorities for the future. The calculations used to create the city’s emissions projections haven’t been released yet, but the Office of Sustainability is preparing to release more information about the specific format and protocol of the community emissions inventory. Also, they tried to help identify datasets that Open Austin members could analyze or publicize to help the city reach its emissions goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Austin Energy’s reports of emissions from large point sources are reliable and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/ghgreporting&quot;&gt;available through the EPA&lt;/a&gt;, but this covers only about 20 sites in the Austin area. The city data portal also has several &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/browse?q=ECAD&amp;amp;sortBy=relevance&amp;amp;page=1&quot;&gt;ECAD (Energy Conservation Audit and Disclosure) datasets&lt;/a&gt;, which include energy audits for large commercial buildings. &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/City-Government/Travis-County-Community-wide-Greenhouse-Gas-Emissi/3maj-7ecz&quot;&gt;Austin’s community greenhouse gas inventory&lt;/a&gt; previously has been done every three years, but they hope to do it each year from now on. It’s based on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iclei.org/activities/agendas/low-carbon-city/gpc.html&quot;&gt;Global Protocol for Community-Scale Greenhouse Gas Emission Inventories (GPC)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city analysts said they thought transportation emissions would be the most interesting category for an Open Austin project. Of course, the city’s beliefs about transportations emissions in the city are mostly based on modeling rather than direct measurements. The best model is probably the Transportation Demand Model that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capcog.org/data-maps-and-reports/publications/&quot;&gt;Capital Area Council of Governments&lt;/a&gt; has developed for the region. Texas A&amp;amp;M did the last run of that model. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://austintexas.gov/tdm&quot;&gt;Austin Transportation Department&lt;/a&gt; should also have relevant data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city analysts explained that the city’s emissions analysis is based on a combination of high-level models and specific project-level studies. So when they estimate a certain project will result in emissions reductions, they have to simply subtract those savings from the high-level model’s estimate of the city’s emissions. That means they don’t usually have a way to test whether the assumptions in the the project-level studies would interact with other factors in the citywide model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city’s transportation emissions model doesn’t currently incorporate any data from traffic monitoring systems such as Waze or Google Maps, but the Office of Sustainability would like to incorporate that kind of data if they could. They’d also be interested in researching the emissions effect of shared riding in autonomous electric vehicles, since one study indicated that a shift to electric vehicles would increase the load on Austin Energy by only 28 percent. Other future work from the city might include a model of the number of people that live in transit corridors, in connection with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.austintexas.gov/codenext&quot;&gt;CodeNext&lt;/a&gt;. In short, there are still many gaps in the city’s knowledge about community emissions that could be filled with more data and more research. If a project team develops around emissions data in Open Austin or through &lt;a href=&quot;http://atxhackforchange.org/&quot;&gt;ATX Hack for Change&lt;/a&gt;, they should feel free to contact the Office of Sustainability for an insider’s understanding of the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Continue the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Austin’s advocacy agenda is intended to help get access to data resources based on community members’ demonstrated interest in finding creative ways to use them for the public benefit. Now that the city has given helpful guidance about greenhouse emissions data, it’s a good time to build a project around that data at an Open Austin event like a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/events/247367149/&quot;&gt;Community Action Night&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/events/zfmdhpyxgbkb/&quot;&gt;Civic Hack Saturday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the discussion in the Open Austin community on Slack: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Get an invite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP for our future events on Meetup: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2018/02/24/office-of-sustainability-offers-guidance-for-civic-climate-data</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2018/02/24/office-of-sustainability-offers-guidance-for-civic-climate-data</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Austin Releases Joint Advocacy Agenda with Austin Tech Alliance</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.austintech.org/&quot;&gt;Austin Tech Alliance&lt;/a&gt; and Open Austin &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.austintech.org/austin-tech-alliance-open-austin-release-joint-advocacy-agenda/&quot;&gt;released a joint policy agenda&lt;/a&gt; with four requests for data transparency from the City of Austin. The requests are “Make City Council meeting agendas and vote data more accessible,” “Publish lobbyist activity reports and registration data,” “Support researchers’ access to raw data from city surveys,” and “Publish data used to produce the greenhouse gas emissions inventories under the Austin Community Climate Plan.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All four of these policy objectives relate to disclosures of data that Open Austin volunteers have been interested in helping to share with the public. A common theme is that we’ve hit some roadblocks with projects in these areas, and we think that further action by the city could have a positive impact. Here’s the text of the requests we presented to the city, along with some background information about the work that people in the Open Austin community have been doing with the four categories of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;city-council-meeting-agendas-and-vote-data&quot;&gt;City Council meeting agendas and vote data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What: City Council agendas and minutes should be easily navigable and searchable with persistent ID codes for items that come under consideration in multiple meetings and public meeting information for each phase of decision making. Council members’ votes should be released in an open data format.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Why: With improved navigation and ease of accessing vote histories, residents will better be able to follow an issue or specific policy debate as it progresses through the policy making process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Austin’s efforts to publish data about items on the city council agenda included a 2015 hackathon prototype called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/council-connect&quot;&gt;Council Connect&lt;/a&gt;, which failed because it was hard to collect the needed data from the city’s website. The problem has attracted &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/project-ideas/issues/94&quot;&gt;continued interest&lt;/a&gt; among Open Austin members. Data collection is already easier than it used to be, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.open-austin.org/blog/2017/10/05/changes-in-access-to-Austins-local-legislative-data&quot;&gt;explained in a recent Open Austin blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lobbyist-activity-reports-and-registration-data&quot;&gt;Lobbyist activity reports and registration data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What: The lobbyist registration dataset on the city data portal at data.austintexas.gov was recently modified to delete most records prior to 2017 and omit the names of the clients that hired the lobbyists. The city should restore access to those records. Also, recent lobbyist activity reports are now available online only in PDF format. The city should extract the contents of those reports and post them on the data portal.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Why: Disclosure of lobbying datasets allows public access to information showing who is influencing decision makers, providing residents with a more complete picture of the public policy process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Austin produced a few, mostly experimental, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.open-austin.org/projects/lobbying-in-austin.html&quot;&gt;visualizations from the available data&lt;/a&gt; about lobbyists on the city and state level. Those experiments led us to conclude that Council Member Pool’s 2016 lobby reform proposal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.open-austin.org/blog/2016/06/12/finding-a-story-in-austins-lobbying-data&quot;&gt;would help the data published by the city form an accurate portrayal of actual lobbyist activity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;raw-data-from-city-surveys&quot;&gt;Raw data from city surveys&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What: Survey data, such as the City of Austin Community Survey, should be made publicly accessible in appropriate formats, including raw data, data maps, questionnaires, and details about survey methodology. Survey data should include demographic questions but not capture any personally identifiable information, preserving the anonymity of individual respondents. For instance, when the city uses an online platform for public deliberation about the city budget, anonymized feedback captured by the tool should be downloadable as open data for analysis by the public.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Why: Transparent survey methods and data can help to determine whether the survey reached a representative sample of respondents. Researchers might also use them to determine whether the results can be merged together with other datasets to support a larger study, such as a study comparing community services in multiple cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://austinbudget.party/home&quot;&gt;Budget Party&lt;/a&gt; is an Open Austin application used to help people understand and augment a city budget for Austin. Best used in context of an in-person “Budget Party” event, the Budget Party application is intended to facilitate deliberation and collect residents’ opinions as structured data. Also, Open Austin supports access to government data for social science research in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;greenhouse-gas-emissions-data&quot;&gt;Greenhouse gas emissions data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What: The City should release the data underlying the Community Climate Plan Progress Updates and the City’s calculated progress on its goal of net-zero community-wide greenhouse gas emissions by 2050. This could include site-specific estimates of energy consumption or resulting emissions, or estimates of the emissions reductions from implementing efficiency programs at particular sites.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Why: Disclosure would give residents enough information to evaluate the city’s estimates of the amount of emissions avoided by various categories of efficiency programs. It would also help evaluate the city’s projections of future emissions and identify emissions policy priorities for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mayor Adler recently reaffirmed the city’s goal to have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://kxan.com/2017/11/28/austin-and-georgetown-mayors-talk-renewable-impacts-and-climate-change/&quot;&gt;cumulative net zero carbon footprint by 2050&lt;/a&gt;, and a sense of crisis about environmental issues is one common reason that Open Austin members give for their interest in open data. Despite that, no civic technolocy project about climate change has ever moved beyond the early experimental phase in Open Austin. One reason for that absence could be that the city hasn’t yet released the best possible data for measuring the city’s progress on its Community Climate Plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To determine whether the city is making progress on reducing emissions, a researcher needs to measure not just the actual emissions, but also the emissions that have been avoided due to the city’s environmental policies. The city has several good datasets about actual emissions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/Utilities-and-City-Services/Emissions-By-Plant/ukf5-i76d/data&quot;&gt;emissions by plant&lt;/a&gt;, which is aggregated into &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/Utilities-and-City-Services/CO2-emissions-by-year/e25g-t5zh&quot;&gt;emissions by year&lt;/a&gt;, calculated as metric tons of carbon dioxide equivalents (CO2-eq).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/Utilities-and-City-Services/Carbon-Intensity/hetr-8wqd&quot;&gt;carbon intensity&lt;/a&gt;, calculated as the average CO2-eq per kilowatt-hour generated.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/City-Government/Municipal-Carbon-Footprint/acyh-8suc&quot;&gt;Carbon footprint for nine categories of municipal operations&lt;/a&gt;, as CO2-eq.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/City-Government/Travis-County-Community-wide-Greenhouse-Gas-Emissi/3maj-7ecz&quot;&gt;Travis County Community-wide Greenhouse Gas Emissions Inventory&lt;/a&gt;. This dataset contains just three rows of summary statistics, but it covers eight broad categories, it’s calculated as CO2-eq, and it’s not limited to municipal operations.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As the &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/open-austin/office-of-sustainability-offers-guidance-for-civic-climate-data-2faf348efef4&quot;&gt;Office of Sustainability told us&lt;/a&gt; after this post was originally written, there are also several &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/browse?q=ECAD&amp;amp;sortBy=relevance&amp;amp;page=1&quot;&gt;ECAD (Energy Conservation Audit and Disclosure) datasets&lt;/a&gt;, which include energy audits for large commercial buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other side of the calculation is emissions avoided by following different parts of the climate plan. The city reports:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/Utilities-and-City-Services/Energy-Efficiency-Avoided-Emissions-2012/69ir-67ws&quot;&gt;Emissions avoided in 2012 by various categories of efficiency programs&lt;/a&gt;. This appears to be in real tons of emissions, not CO2 equivalents.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/City-Government/Economy-Creativity-Avoided-emissions-from-plug-in-/wqg5-bweh&quot;&gt;Avoided emissions from plug-in network charges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A very small dataset about &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/Utilities-and-City-Services/Austin-Resource-Recovery-Telework-Pilot/ac5x-csd7&quot;&gt;emissions prevented by a telework pilot program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dataset about emissions avoided through efficiency programs has a lot of useful information, but it only covers the year 2012, which was prior to the adoption of the Community Climate Plan in 2015. (In 2012, Austin Energy was operating under the earlier “&lt;a href=&quot;https://austinenergy.com/ae/about/environment/austin-climate-protection-plan&quot;&gt;Austin Climate Protection Plan&lt;/a&gt;.”) Also, some of the dataset’s categories of efficiency programs are broad or vague, and it’s not clear what methodology was used for attributing emissions reductions to various categories. It would also be helpful for the city to clarify when each efficiency program began so researchers could try to isolate the impact from each program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s understandable that the city can’t afford to commission exhaustive studies on every aspect of Austin’s greenhouse gas emissions. But when the city publishes summary statistics like the ones in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/City-Government/Travis-County-Community-wide-Greenhouse-Gas-Emissi/3maj-7ecz&quot;&gt;Community-wide Greenhouse Gas Emissions Inventory&lt;/a&gt;, it appears that the information being published might be just the tip of the iceberg, and that the city must possess much more supporting data that it used to calculate the summary statistics. If more of that kind of data was available to the public, it could spark civic technologists’ creativity in finding new ways to measure Austin’s carbon efficiency, and help climate sustainability become a more quantifiable part of local policy discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Continue the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in a civic project involving the transparency issues in our policy agenda? Or do you know of available data that we’re missing? Get in touch if you think you can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the discussion in the Open Austin community on Slack: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Get an invite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To join one of our civic projects or work on one of your own, come to one of our Civic Hack Night or Civic Hack Saturday events. For policy and community discussion, come to an “Open Gov &amp;amp; Civic Tech” meetup. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;RSVP for these events on Meetup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2017/12/04/Open-Austin-Releases-Joint-Advocacy-Agenda-With-Austin-Tech-Alliance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2017/12/04/Open-Austin-Releases-Joint-Advocacy-Agenda-With-Austin-Tech-Alliance</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Changes in Access to Austin's Local Legislative Data</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When newcomers to Open Austin decide they’re interested in taking on a civic hacking project, one of the most common suggestions they offer is to make our city council’s agendas more accessible. It has the potential to be a very visible and impactful project, but the people who have worked on it have found that it’s harder than it seems it needs to be. Austin has historically managed its council agenda with an old software tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://austin.siretechnologies.com/sirepub/mtgviewer.aspx?meetid=1541&amp;amp;doctype=Agenda&quot;&gt;SIRE&lt;/a&gt;. Collecting the agenda text and supporting documents was a matter of navigating through a network of links to PDFs: not an easy task to automate. And change in this area was somewhat hard to achieve because responsibility for city legislative records was divided between the council itself, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.austintexas.gov/department/city-clerk&quot;&gt;city clerk’s office&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.austintexas.gov/department/supporting-city-councils-work-agenda-office&quot;&gt;agenda office&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city took a step toward accessibility last year when it began &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/City-Government/Austin-City-Council-Agenda-Items/es7e-878h&quot;&gt;posting the text of the agenda items&lt;/a&gt; to the city data portal. But the data portal isn’t always a welcoming place for residents who just want easy access to information about civic issues. When the city had an opportunity to solicit bids for a new agenda management system, Open Austin &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1FOLuCR6kRRTLQD5dyJCuIquRkEoaGi0aqAVlBFwVuPY/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;sent a letter&lt;/a&gt; recommending a set of features the city should look for: an open API or bulk downloads, use of a widely accepted data format such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://opencivicdata.readthedocs.io/en/latest/index.html&quot;&gt;the “Open Civic Data” standard&lt;/a&gt;, and easy exports to calendar client formats like iCal, Outlook, and Google Calendar. The city took action to improve the council’s website by selecting a new software vendor called &lt;a href=&quot;https://granicus.com/solutions/meeting-agenda-suite/peak-agenda-management/&quot;&gt;Granicus&lt;/a&gt;, but technical problems have bogged down that project and the new system (called Legistar) still isn’t live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the new system still isn’t expected to have all the features available on some other Legistar systems, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://legistar.council.nyc.gov/&quot;&gt;New York’s&lt;/a&gt;: it won’t reveal how each council member voted on the matters before the council, and it won’t assign unique ID numbers to the agenda items for readers to track them from one council meeting to another. Also, an apparent miscommunication led the city to stop updating the dataset on the data portal even though the new system hadn’t yet come online to replace it. David Edmonson of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.austintech.org/&quot;&gt;Austin Tech Alliance&lt;/a&gt; stepped in and spoke with the city clerk’s office about restoring access to the agenda dataset. The city was very helpful, and they restored access to the missing data with ongoing updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around the same time, Open Austin members noticed that another dataset we had been exploring had been taken offline: this time, it was the identities of the entities who hired lobbyists to lobby the city government. This information was once disclosed as part of the city’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/City-Government/Lobbyists-Master-List-of-Lobbyists/96z6-upac/data&quot;&gt;lobbyist registration dataset&lt;/a&gt;. Today, that dataset only identifies the people registered with the city as lobbyists, but it no longer identifies whom they’re working for. Finding the identities of the clients requires navigating a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ci.austin.tx.us/cityclerk/lobbyist/index.cfm&quot;&gt;web database&lt;/a&gt;, which is much more challenging than just clicking a single download button. (And as &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1nJZ1y4YPiNpuHpoduCIPpF-oF_qOPp8UmDswiEbN-Ts/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Open Austin’s policy agenda&lt;/a&gt; points out, we’d like for the published dataset to include not just the identities of the clients, but the entire lobbyist activity reports.) Although Austinites are lucky enough to have a city government that’s serious about the quality of the web services it offers to the public, Austin is still several steps away from offering comprehensive accessible data about the local legislative process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Continue the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have a project that makes use of Austin’s city council or lobbyist datasets? Tell us about it in the #p-lobbyist-campaign channel of the Open Austin community on Slack: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Get an invite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see an example of a (non-open source) visualization of city council data that grew out of an Open Austin project, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://minutes.city/#/city/austin&quot;&gt;minutes.city&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP for our future events on Meetup: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/dawilson/3017994876&quot;&gt;“Austin City Hall” by Dave Wilson&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC-ND 2.0&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2017/10/05/changes-in-access-to-Austins-local-legislative-data</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2017/10/05/changes-in-access-to-Austins-local-legislative-data</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Projects and management</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We need to overhaul our project management. To get there, and to work in the open, let’s start by clearly defining the problem, the fundamental challenges, and our circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Open Austin, our projects are for public good and made in the open. Compared to many open source projects that are often for developers, by developers, our projects often involve a more diverse roster of stakeholders like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Advocates&lt;/em&gt;: people who are passionate about a subject and act as an intermediary between those affected and other (potential) stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Designers&lt;/em&gt;: people who improve or make new experiences and things through human-centered methods&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Programmers&lt;/em&gt;: people who make old machines learn new tricks with high-level markup, low-level assembly, and everything in between&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Researchers&lt;/em&gt;: people who focus on understanding and articulating subjects, problems, and ways to achieve a goal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Subject matter experts (SMEs)&lt;/em&gt;: people who have a deep or broad knowledge about a subject or specific problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Code for America brigade, we share the common value of &lt;em&gt;civic hacking&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeforamerica.org/blog/2013/06/07/defining-civic-hacking/&quot;&gt;working quickly and creatively to help improve government&lt;/a&gt;. As a member of that brigade, though, I would like to challenge that a little, in that we ought to help improve &lt;em&gt;governance&lt;/em&gt;, not government. That is, we could be slightly more focused on how individuals, things, and societies self-govern or do work themselves toward a &lt;a href=&quot;http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=1900448&quot;&gt;public thing&lt;/a&gt; (not necessarily government-managed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How might that shift in organizational focus, and subsequent work, affect government apparatus and how people interact with them? Our stakeholder interaction so far reaches mostly to municipal levels of government and individuals interested in civic work. Perhaps our less conventional processes are not palatable enough yet for more direct intervention in government business, but one important feature of our process is changing how people perceive and interact with public things through &lt;em&gt;hacking&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a community, we consider any of these stakeholders as civic hackers―quick and creative folks who innovate and push boundaries. However that may not lend well to achieving goals that are more specifically scoped or more &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niftycom.org/uploads/5/8/8/9/5889962/wicked_problems_design_thinking.pdf&quot;&gt;wicked&lt;/a&gt;. Achieving these goals requires some management to integrate an often variable alliance of people, things, actions, and environments as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mitpressjournals.org/doi/pdf/10.1162/desi.2009.25.1.48&quot;&gt;publics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trouble is many of our projects don’t have project management help, though many have requested it. Without it, those projects could (and have) fall into an unrecoverable state. Whereas one stakeholder might only need to know the particulars of their own work, managing projects requires some degree of knowledge to all work. Fortunately, managing isn’t something only a human can do. We do specialize in technology after all, and project management tech is welcome to take the load off the organization’s leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notably, across all Code for America and Open Austin materials, all signs point members to tools for project management rather than people. While we have project leads, they are often primarily one of the five aforementioned types of stakeholders rather than a “manager.” Instead, our project management has been developed over the last year based on various frameworks that informed our own &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.open-austin.org/civic-tech-canvas/&quot;&gt;Civic Tech Project Planning Canvas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This canvas is a framework for users to articulate their problem, proposed solution, and logistics required to realize it. Essentially, it helped define the &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; of a project. The problems often come from SMEs and advocates, who may also come to the table with a proposed solution that is then articulated through collaborating with other stakeholders at Open Austin meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following this initial canvas-building, we suggest teams borrow from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://begriffs.com/posts/2016-01-29-making-twenty-percent-time-work.html&quot;&gt;BASEDEF&lt;/a&gt; framework to consider how to do work incrementally instead of over-scoping or working privately for so long others forget what they’re doing. This is important considering the asynchronous, remote, and variable work that often loses information from meeting to meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;issues-and-improvements&quot;&gt;Issues and improvements&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many projects at Open Austin are never completed or delivered to external stakeholders, and many others languish after contributors, champions, or material support are disengaged. This is to be expected from a volunteer group, and it’s actually not too big of a deal when it comes to our values. When I first joined the team, I actually poked people a little too hard to figure out why they hadn’t shared their progress (or any update) with the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I toned it down a bit after we discussed what our values were and what we commit, as an organization, to members and friends in the community. However, we would like to have more of an impact on our communities, which requires us to build trust with them, which requires more discipline in how we manage to complete projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early in 2017, after discussing this issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/iced-coffee/issues/69&quot;&gt;among our leadership team&lt;/a&gt; and other &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/19HncsnlAR5reLH0iul7oi-_tX7Cer-6Y0WCEZ_kkYTU/edit&quot;&gt;Code for America leaders&lt;/a&gt;, we put together an agenda to change how we might be more effective at managing our projects and, more fundamentally, our organization itself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Define what services we offer as an organization and how&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop a project management framework that better articulates expectations with stakeholders and builds trust&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Research legal structures required to accept more impactful work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pilot our nonprofit capabilities with a highly impactful project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pilot our nonprofit organization with a government project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;services-and-values&quot;&gt;Services and values&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our leadership team met to first tackle our problem of value definition: what should we offer, and how do we create value of that to others? We first &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/iced-coffee/issues/218&quot;&gt;reconsidered&lt;/a&gt; how the leadership team itself is organized as a community-driven entity. This helped us to more quickly and effectively &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/iced-coffee/issues/233&quot;&gt;analyze&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/iced-coffee/issues/235&quot;&gt;implement&lt;/a&gt; improvements to our core processes that would help us identify issues with projects and enable their leads to resolve them with or without our help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/iced-coffee/issues/215&quot;&gt;iterated on our organization values&lt;/a&gt;, aligning on our dedication to community-driven policy setting and idea generation, both in terms of what we will and won’t do. The results of these policies and ideas would then be scoped to projects we can accomplish, which then begs the question of management. Following from our civic hacking ethos, our form of management is born from our collective values and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwigruzgvuHSAhUB24MKHU75CbkQFggcMAA&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Ffaculty.nipissingu.ca%2Flindap%2FORGS3706%2Fresources%2FOrganizations_as_Cultures_UV.ppt&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGR1NR9cKgS-Z9XWm9hadtsO4ObVQ&amp;amp;sig2=yN81HLr_5ekYw-kltM8hXg&quot;&gt;cultural organization&lt;/a&gt; rather than the political or mechanical organizations of governments and corporations that we also participate in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To better understand this, we researched how similar organizations managed projects so that we could &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/iced-coffee/issues/224&quot;&gt;design and test our own&lt;/a&gt; process, including the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openoakland.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/OpenOakland-Projects-04.pdf&quot;&gt;Open Oakland’s “Leading a Project”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smartchicagocollaborative.org/collaborative-project-management/&quot;&gt;Smart Chicago’s “Collaborative Project Management”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/codeforamerica/civic-tech-patterns&quot;&gt;Code for America’s “Civic Tech Patterns”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://playbook.cio.gov/&quot;&gt;U.S. Digital Service’s “Playbook”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/design-principles&quot;&gt;U.K. Government Design Service’s “Design Principles”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without our own process, we were not fully realizing our capabilities and opportunities, affecting our mission to quickly and creatively innovate civic services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-project-management-framework&quot;&gt;Our project management framework&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to seeking out peer organizations’ management techniques, we also conducted a more academic literature review. From research by &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/icc/article-lookup/doi/10.1093/icc/dtw004&quot;&gt;Lakemond et al.&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jpim.12125/full&quot;&gt;Wake and Bogers&lt;/a&gt; we found an interesting parallel between their open innovation practices in enterprise and our civic innovation in a volunteer organization. In particular they found that project management is quickly supplanted in importance by knowledge matching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lakemond et al. found that project management had a strong impact on performance in the early stages of a project, such as collaborating during ideation. It was especially important when there were many different stakeholders and contributors, but less so for later stages of a project’s completion. Rather, at these late stages “knowledge matching” may have been more important than project management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge matching in our case could mean sharing Open Austin’s and our partners’ technological competencies and knowledge resources. That might be in the form of workshops, consultations, or training. The function of it though is bidirectional learning and collaboration, which could determine performance on a project at all stages. It may be more determinant, though, at later stages as project management becomes less effective, as Lakemond et al. suggested. For the early stages of projects, including finding problems and ideating around them, we could borrow the expertise of companies that employ people dedicated to project management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wake and Bogers described how companies often seek external sources to help them innovate in the open, including some who turn to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Christopher_Tucci/publication/267027676_Crowdsourcing_As_A_Solution_To_Distant_Search/links/54416fff0cf2a6a049a584a0/Crowdsourcing-As-A-Solution-To-Distant-Search.pdf&quot;&gt;crowd&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/9209/70ac89da9ecd24e567d5d3b90a35ad279b5f.pdf&quot;&gt;intermediaries&lt;/a&gt;.  An example of both are members of Open Austin and other Code for America brigades, as we are a large and diverse group of people who do both &lt;a href=&quot;https://smartech.gatech.edu/bitstream/handle/1853/56292/MENG-DISSERTATION-2016.pdf?sequence=1&amp;amp;isAllowed=y&quot;&gt;technical and social&lt;/a&gt; work. And we regularly work together, often at hack nights, hackathons, and other types of &lt;a href=&quot;http://publications.lib.chalmers.se/records/fulltext/245365/245365.pdf&quot;&gt;innovation jams&lt;/a&gt; to offer this environment to entities in the civic tech space. However, companies often don’t just hop right into this sort of hack environment. They often require an intermediary to guide them and operate in new environments like these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By providing that environmental savviness along with the requisite subject and technical knowledge, we can trade for their project management skills in a project’s early stage, allowing us to at least structure it through some scheduled completion. While this might not be as “complete” as we may expect, it is a step toward that. We and other brigades already do engage companies like this to some degree, but we don’t earn as much in long-term commitment. For example, many companies participate in ATX Hack for Change, but we don’t get quite the same result from that as we do with our community partners like Austin Tech Alliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can do better in the former space by making clear requests for time, artifacts, and communication before we break from jam environments. Increasing engagement in general with those management-savvy hackathon-curious companies may also improve their chances at participating individually as a member or visitor, as well as future organization-level work. This is something to be explored, and presently, companies may not yet be incentivized adequately to work with us on an organizational level. Some outright refuse unless we are legally organized in particular ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All things considered, we can better ensure our projects reach some measure of completion by organizing projects for knowledge matching with external stakeholders. Project management could use more structure in early stages to help organize, while as the project progresses we supplant that structured management with a bespoke &lt;a href=&quot;http://digilib.gmu.edu/jspui/bitstream/handle/1920/10609/Novak_gmu_0883E_11283.pdf?sequence=1&amp;amp;isAllowed=y&quot;&gt;knowledge commons&lt;/a&gt;. We would need to describe that commons policy on an abstract level, involving project governance and knowledge sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first step in this direction has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1OP1Atz3q5GnzjiEJ2JeExKOUrD_oQFzx0HLlopDdxgw/edit#slide=id.p&quot;&gt;a presentation&lt;/a&gt; to our members at a civic tech night. In this, I described how we have managed projects so far and some skills and techniques I learned from Mozilla’s Open Leadership Training. From there, we developed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/project-ideas/blob/master/ISSUE_TEMPLATE.md&quot;&gt;guide and checklist&lt;/a&gt; for sharing project ideas, both for the first time and for progress as the project develops. I also set &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/iced-coffee/wiki/Projects&quot;&gt;policies and checkpoints&lt;/a&gt; for the projects lead position to best facilitate and, if necessary, intervene in a project’s management to fully realize its potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;legal-structure&quot;&gt;Legal structure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do impactful work. We engage with multiple communities year-round, culminating in ATX Hack for Change, and we engage with companies through partnerships like Austin Tech Alliance and CityUp. We also interact with more loosely organized groups like Data for Democracy and other meetups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, more structured entities like businesses, nonprofits, and government may present opportunities that a civic-conscious hacker may not have the visibility and resources for. Those entities, though, often require some legal assurance we’re not going to run off with their money, make them look bad, or come off as unprofessional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make this happen, we need to organize Open Austin more formally, particularly as a 501c3 nonprofit corporation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For about four months we gathered our core values and practices into a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1HwgQ9lDcJohBLZPyRVvMqvf282mGJOGM17KFNkvBmfA/edit&quot;&gt;bylaws document&lt;/a&gt;. Using this, we are now in the process of submitting our paperwork to formally incorporate. As a 501c3, we would be able to do business and participate in other nonprofit programs from corporations and government that require incorporation. We also join a network of other Code For America brigades that have incorporated to share management experience. The process has also been a test for our values, both in the decision to incorporate and how to incorporate our membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that “the corporation” is the entity that owns assets, manages work on behalf of the whole organization, and directs group activities. Practically speaking, it is both inclusive of, but distinct from, what would be called “Open Austin” as has existed as a group of friends, a Meetup group, a civic hacking organization, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering our previous issues with helping Open Austin members, including project leads, manage projects and facilitate their other efforts, we had some trouble deciding whether to include members who weren’t on the leadership team in the corporation. While members would of course intrinsically comprise Open Austin forever, the corporation does not include members other than the board of directors (also known as the “leadership team” or “core team”). Indeed, even our current practices on the leadership team haven’t required oversight by the general membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, there is much to test from here. The incorporation itself takes some months, and we likely wouldn’t take on any major projects in the interim. For example, we also need to consider that major risks come with major opportunities. As such, we are currently working on ways to set indemnification policy such that, if we are sued for unintended or fringe effects of one of our projects, what are our legal and fiscal options? Similarly, if a private or public organization that does not sit well with us asks us to work on a project, how much should our organizational values affect the decision?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;piloting-the-nonprofit-model&quot;&gt;Piloting the nonprofit model&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One successful project from Open Austin is Budget Party, a gamified experience that helps people understand and augment a city budget for Austin. As a pilot for our new organization, how can we test our values, project management, and new organizational structure by working on this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having demonstrated we can operate normally as a nonprofit, and also having discovered new ways we can do civic work, we can then try directly influencing our city government itself. How can we break into this space, how might we change Open Austin in the experience, and what will we find about how government might turn to hacking as a way to improve life for Austinites?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are open questions that I’d like to leave as an exercise for the reader. Consider it a prompt that anyone may contribute to (i.e. we will retweet you or even host your post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-do-you-think&quot;&gt;What do you think?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully having this article around will help other organizations, like other Code for America brigades, organize themselves in a way that innovates how civic hacking communities effectively innovate and collaborate. Let us know if it did or even if this doesn’t sound right at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are your stories of organizing a volunteer group, managing open source projects, and incorporating a nonprofit? We’re always curious and always open. Respond and join the discussion on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Slack team&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2017/09/13/project-management</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2017/09/13/project-management</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kirk Watson Advances Open Government Bills</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.texastribune.org/2017/05/11/texas-senate-unticks-proposals-plug-public-records-loopholes/&quot;&gt;Texas Tribune has reported&lt;/a&gt; that Sen. Kirk Watson, D-Austin, has attached several open government initiatives to a single bill designated &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capitol.state.tx.us/BillLookup/History.aspx?LegSess=85R&amp;amp;Bill=HB2328&quot;&gt;HB 2328&lt;/a&gt;, which has passed the Texas Senate. The amended bill now goes back to the House for its approval. The provisions now attached to HB 2328 include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;getting rid of the requirement for a governmental body to get an attorney general opinion before withholding information under the Public Information Act, if it makes a good faith determination that an exception applies.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;changing the Public Information Act’s exception for contract bids, so that the exception doesn’t apply once a contract is awarded.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;including some contractors in the definition of a “governmental body” obligated to respond to record requests.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;mandating public access to government information stored on privately-owned accounts and devices.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;providing that public records containing dates of birth can still be disclosed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;creating a procedure for the Attorney General to compel a response to a public records request.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.texastribune.org/2017/05/11/texas-senate-unticks-proposals-plug-public-records-loopholes/&quot;&gt;The Tribune&lt;/a&gt; has the full story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Continue the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the #policy channel of the Open Austin community on Slack: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Get an invite&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
RSVP for our future events on Meetup: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2017/05/13/kirk-watson-advances-open-government-bills</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2017/05/13/kirk-watson-advances-open-government-bills</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mozilla’s Open Leadership Training can work for Open Austin projects</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I joined the Open Austin leadership team, one of my first goals was to identify specific problems in our project management that might impact members’ ability or motivation to contribute. Early on we defined that problem to be that most project ideas are never completed. However, recently we took a good look at what we are as a community and what we want to facilitate. In doing so, we realized that it’s okay for &lt;em&gt;ideas&lt;/em&gt; to not be completed; they’re just ideas after all. Rather, it’s a problem when a &lt;em&gt;project&lt;/em&gt; that has made commitments or set expectations never gets completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://andyhub.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/project-ideas-750x582.png&quot; alt=&quot;A snapshot of recently updated project ideas on Open Austin’’s Github&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;A snapshot of recently updated project ideas on Open Austin’’s Github&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have completed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.open-austin.org/projects&quot;&gt;dozens of projects&lt;/a&gt; over the years, and there are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/project-ideas/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+sort%3Aupdated-desc+label%3A%22Active+Project%22&quot;&gt;many more&lt;/a&gt; actively worked on today. However, there are all together still more ideas that have been abandoned, shelved for later, or need leadership. We decided that it’s okay for ideas to be this way, in fact it’s great to have pages of unled or abandoned ideas that a newcomer could pick up and run with. However, it becomes a problem when that newcomer doesn’t have the initiative to start on a new project with no help or to continue working on a project that nobody else wants to participate in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-management-issues&quot;&gt;Project management issues&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another problem is when projects that have progressed past just an idea or that have commitments, funding, or external stakeholders are not satisfactorily completed. From some less than rigorous study and experience with this over some years, I’ve identified five causes that have prevented projects from being completed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unmet technical requirements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lost client or target group&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Analysis paralysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lost interest or commitment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dropped out of the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;unmet-technical-requirements&quot;&gt;Unmet technical requirements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the most clear problem that often has an easy to understand solution: you get the right technology, right person, or right information to move forward or pivot. For example, Rails (and thus Ruby) was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog/2047-language-trends-on-github&quot;&gt;popular&lt;/a&gt; new language for web development around the time Code for America started up. This led to a lot of new projects in our communities being developed with Rails. But it didn’t last, and now as other languages and tools have usurped its trendiness, Rails projects may struggle a little harder than others as new members are less interested in contributing to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having the right person with technical knowledge and techniques can be just as important as the project’s tools. It can mean the difference between a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technical_debt&quot;&gt;tech-debted&lt;/a&gt; prototype and a well-engineered project that requires less attention over time, which helps for volunteer projects like ours. Having the right person with the insider technical knowledge also falls under this category. For example, a project for a government body will likely move extremely slowly without the technical knowledge of its legal or procurement matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lost-client-or-target-group&quot;&gt;Lost client or target group&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of our completed projects had at least one external stakeholder, including government workers, nonprofits, and community groups. Without dedicated support and communication affordances to maintain that relationship, a project can easily lose steam. Maintaining relationships is hard, but it affects nearly all aspects of a project for better or worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A client can provide direction, a target group can provide research, a stakeholder can provide technical resources, and it can be too hard to replace them before volunteers move on to something more fulfilling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;analysis-paralysis&quot;&gt;Analysis paralysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A challenge to all agile teams is keeping track of their own time and project management. A team practicing waterfall might work well by seeking volunteers only for the near term objectives and then different volunteers for later objectives, but that requires strong leadership over a long time. An agile, iterative project requires shorter management terms but also means the team must know how and when to observe, reflect, make, and repeat over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overcoming paralysis requires the agency to continue even if they lose the ability to seek clarification from a client or target group. Or if the client provides this but not strong direction, a team may spend too much time observing and reflecting. Then they risk never &lt;em&gt;making&lt;/em&gt; anything. Having the discipline to prototype and potentially throw it all away after testing is critical to iterative work with less managerial overhead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lost-interest-or-commitment&quot;&gt;Lost interest or commitment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a more personal level, it’s just hard to stay engaged in a project that loses its novelty. A new project idea to someone is a great motivator to learn, but depending on what they did or did not learn, that motivation can fizzle out. Time management is also critical here as we are a volunteer organization that is focused on personal projects over business-driven projects. Those who don’t align themselves accordingly may suffer from how they perceive the community and vice-versa. This can happen to regular members, leaders, and external stakeholders, each with their own repercussions to their project and the whole community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dropped-out-of-the-community&quot;&gt;Dropped out of the community&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, churn is the greatest enemy to any subscription-based endeavor. When people leave something, it’s extremely difficult to get them back, and sometimes they leave with something of great value to the community. That can be replaced in time usually, but in the meantime the consequences can cascade. If someone just ghosted, that also draws concern on a more personal level. As an intentional community based on personal projects, it can affect folks on a more emotional level that isn’t so replaceable. Maintaining a personable level of engagement is critical to a healthy community that significantly affects the other four issues I’ve described.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*duMR4WTab-dVqkH8xYUdpw.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Image by Mozilla.&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image by Mozilla.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learning-from-mozilla&quot;&gt;Learning from Mozilla&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Open Austin’s core are our values of open source work and open participation. We share a lot of that with Mozilla, who’s also a great example of getting things done themselves and by enabling others in their own efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a leader in open project leadership, they offer this as a sort of service via their &lt;a href=&quot;https://mozilla.github.io/open-leadership-training-series/&quot;&gt;open leadership training series&lt;/a&gt; (OLTS). I enrolled with my &lt;a href=&quot;https://andyhub.com/concepts/mobile-reporting/&quot;&gt;Mobile-Map-IO&lt;/a&gt; project in their third cohort, which included a couple dozen other participants from around the world. One of the first activities we did was align our values for our individual projects with the community’s values, particularly with Mozilla’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://internethealthreport.org/v01/&quot;&gt;internet health report&lt;/a&gt; categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2017/03/15/five-issues-that-will-determine-the-future-of-internet-health/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://andyhub.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/Internet_Health_issues_march_2017_cover-1400x770-750x413.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mozilla’s Internet Health Report (image by Mozilla)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mozilla’s Internet Health Report (image by Mozilla)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The training series overall is about learning the best practices for working in the open, specifically people who are starting up or leading a project. It’s a mix of a few things, mostly captured by a sort of multimedia &lt;a href=&quot;https://mozilla.github.io/open-leadership-training-series/&quot;&gt;readme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://andyhub.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/olts-readme-750x422.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of the OLTS readme&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Screenshot of the OLTS readme&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reference this readme at nearly every cohort check-in, where we all meet virtually via Vidyo and type on Etherpad, a real-time collaborative notepad, when we have questions or are responding to prompts provided by our lead &lt;a href=&quot;https://acabunoc.github.io/&quot;&gt;Abby&lt;/a&gt;. Before we meet, she sends two options for the whole cohort to meet, giving us a chance to schedule one or the the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://andyhub.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/olt3week4convoscreenshot-750x422.png&quot; alt=&quot;A usual video chat with the whole OLTS cohort&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;A usual video chat with the whole OLTS cohort&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, she prepares &lt;a href=&quot;https://public.etherpad-mozilla.org/p/olt3-trainings&quot;&gt;our cohort Etherpad&lt;/a&gt; with the meeting outline and spaces for us to respond to questions. This gives us chances to participate verbally as well as textually in the conversation, engaging individuals from what they type directly instead of relying on individuals who choose to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://andyhub.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/etherpadscreenshot-750x422.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of how we use Etherpad&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Screenshot of how we use Etherpad&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As leaders, it’s important that we learn from and motivate each other. This live document editing is bolstered by more in-depth artifacts developed from these prompts and those listed on the readme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, we crafted vision statements, articulated the problems we want to address, and more so that others in the community can better understand the motivation, expected outcomes, and progress without the leaders being present. My Mobile Map IO artifacts are all available on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://andyhub.com/concepts/mobile-reporting/&quot;&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;applying-this-with-open-austin&quot;&gt;Applying this with Open Austin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The artifacts are also something we can use to check ourselves, as this is generally only what we spend about 20% of our free time on. Keeping tabs on what commitments we can make in our 20% time is something I think we at Open Austin do well by using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/cheatsheet-basedef&quot;&gt;BASEDEF&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt; logging, &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt; pplying, &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt; uggesting, &lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt; xtending, &lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt; ocumenting, &lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt; vangelizing, and &lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt; ixing are all ways folks can get involved in an idea for civic innovation. What I’m doing now for example is the B, for blogging, to share what I learned and how I could contribute to our process for improving the issues I’ve outlined. These artifacts we created are examples of the BASEDEF spec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://andyhub.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/MMIO-Open-Canvas-750x422.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Open Canvas for my project, similar to the popular Lean and Business Model Canvases.&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Open Canvas for my project, similar to the popular Lean and Business Model Canvases.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another artifact we in OLTS used for maintaining a project is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mozilla.github.io/open-leadership-training-series/articles/opening-your-project/develop-an-open-project-strategy-with-open-canvas/&quot;&gt;Open Canvas&lt;/a&gt;, something similar to what Open Austin has iterated on with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.open-austin.org/civic-tech-canvas/&quot;&gt;Civic Tech Project Planning Canvas&lt;/a&gt;. The canvas can also inform a roadmap, which we started building from day one to guide our direction. In order to deliver (i.e. complete to a degree) a minimally viable experience to a stakeholder, the project team must align on some near- and long-term goals that are defined in a way that stakeholders would care about. Instead of defining technical requirements or jargon-laden statements, an experience-based roadmap should define what a stakeholder would be able to do or experience at each milestone. Defining this way may help with keeping them engaged and acting as good designers, not just good hackers. And this is important, because it’s hard as a stakeholder or user to wait for volunteer―&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.academia.edu/8728551/Hack_for_good_Speculative_labor_app_development_and_the_burden_of_austerity&quot;&gt;often speculative&lt;/a&gt;―labor to yield a desirable experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, one last OLTS artifact that I felt was important was understanding what we would find welcoming or helpful when first reading about a project. Community is at the center of leading an open project, and without a welcoming experience to that community, a project therein may fail to catch new members. This makes well-designed and welcoming documentation a very high priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sanfranannie/4136379024&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://andyhub.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/sanfranannie-750x563.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo by Ann Larie Valentine.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by Ann Larie Valentine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common way of providing this is with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mozilla.github.io/open-leadership-training-series/articles/opening-your-project/write-a-great-project-readme/&quot;&gt;readme&lt;/a&gt;, a pleasant way of greeting someone into your project’s home, like the OLTS website. Removing the jargon from our roadmap, readme, and other artifacts is especially important for us because Open Austin is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/lunch-and-learn-with-the-austin-innovation-office-designing-for-the-100-tickets-32426014081&quot;&gt;designing for the 100%&lt;/a&gt;: everyone in our city. And like any house’s rules defined on their doormat, we could also define a code of conduct and contribution guidelines to entice folks to start making contributions in any BASEDEF way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, half of the experience of OLTS is having my mentor &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MinnSoe&quot;&gt;Minn&lt;/a&gt; who knows my name, knows my project, and wants to help me succeed. Even though I may start losing motivation, having someone asking me questions and injecting enthusiasm is hugely helpful to staying on point. Part of his goal is to get me ready for Mozilla’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://mozilla.github.io/global-sprint/&quot;&gt;Global Sprint&lt;/a&gt;. Knowing that my project’s going to be part of some big thing way in advance is a great motivator. Open Austin does something similar with &lt;a href=&quot;http://atxhackforchange.org/&quot;&gt;ATX Hack for Change&lt;/a&gt;, but we don’t really talk it up until the weeks leading up to the event. With a more personal welcoming experience, a constant personal peer presence, and a long-term goal to set, we might see some improvements in membership retention and engagement levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-suggestions&quot;&gt;Some suggestions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I have six big takeaways from Mozilla’s OLTS for Open Austin. These are the things I’d like to help lead in our organization:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Motivation and alignment with shared community values&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Framework for starting a project from an idea&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Regular engagement with the whole community&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ample community technology and resources&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mentor who knows you and provides 1-on-1 experience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High-exposure events to nudge long-term goal setting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published at &lt;a href=&quot;https://andyhub.com/archive/mozillas-open-leadership-training-can-work-for-open-austin-projects/&quot;&gt;https://andyhub.com/archive/mozillas-open-leadership-training-can-work-for-open-austin-projects/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2017/04/23/mozillas-open-leadership-training-can-work-for-open-austin-projects</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2017/04/23/mozillas-open-leadership-training-can-work-for-open-austin-projects</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lege Schedules Transparency Bills for Public Hearings</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since last month when we published an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.open-austin.org/blog/2017/03/19/open_government_under_debate_in_tx_legislature&quot;&gt;overview of open government bills&lt;/a&gt; in the state Legislature, one of the bills we’ve been watching has passed the House, one has passed the Senate, one has been rewritten, and seven have been scheduled for public hearings to be held on Monday and Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;passed&quot;&gt;Passed:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Thursday, the House passed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/BillLookup/History.aspx?LegSess=85R&amp;amp;Bill=HB3107&quot;&gt;HB 3107&lt;/a&gt;, which lets government bodies impose limits on the amount of records they’re required to disclose to a single requestor per month or year (unless the requestors prove they’re employees of news organizations).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On March 29, the Senate passed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/BillLookup/History.aspx?LegSess=85R&amp;amp;Bill=SB407&quot;&gt;SB 407&lt;/a&gt;, which would allow disclosure of contract bids under the Public Information Act after the contract was awarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;out-of-committee&quot;&gt;Out of Committee:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/BillLookup/History.aspx?LegSess=85R&amp;amp;Bill=HB2328&quot;&gt;HB 2328&lt;/a&gt; is an important bill that’s now out of committee. It would get rid of the requirement for a governmental body to get an attorney general opinion before withholding information under the Public Information Act, if it makes a good faith determination that an exception applies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/BillLookup/History.aspx?LegSess=85R&amp;amp;Bill=HB1258&quot;&gt;HB 1258&lt;/a&gt;, which previously would have prevented anyone from setting up online access to court records currently held by counties, has now been &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/BillLookup/History.aspx?LegSess=85R&amp;amp;Bill=HB1258&quot;&gt;rewritten and toned down&lt;/a&gt;. The current version appears to apply only to the state government. It would allow the state to add new court documents to its database, but it would require the state to get permission from the counties to add the backlog of old documents. Also, when the state collects a fee for public access to court documents, it would have to hand the money over to the counties. This bill &lt;a href=&quot;https://openstates.org/tx/bills/85/HB1258/?show_all_sponsors=True&quot;&gt;now has 44 sponsors&lt;/a&gt; out of the 150 total representatives, and it is out of committee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;scheduled-for-hearing&quot;&gt;Scheduled for Hearing:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, the House Government Transparency and Operation Committee &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/Committees/MeetingsUpcoming.aspx?Chamber=H&quot;&gt;will hold public hearings&lt;/a&gt; on six open records bills:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/BillLookup/History.aspx?LegSess=85R&amp;amp;Bill=HB526&quot;&gt;HB 526&lt;/a&gt;, which would amend the Public Information Act to entitle only residents to public information.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/BillLookup/Actions.aspx?LegSess=85R&amp;amp;Bill=HB793&quot;&gt;HB 792&lt;/a&gt;, which is similar to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/BillLookup/History.aspx?LegSess=85R&amp;amp;Bill=SB407&quot;&gt;SB 407&lt;/a&gt;, and would allow disclosure of contract bids under the Public Information Act after the contract was awarded.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/BillLookup/Actions.aspx?LegSess=85R&amp;amp;Bill=HB793&quot;&gt;HB 793&lt;/a&gt;, extending the Public Information Act to cover some privately-owned government contractors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/BillLookup/History.aspx?LegSess=85R&amp;amp;Bill=HB2670&quot;&gt;HB 2670&lt;/a&gt;, supporting public access to government information stored on privately-owned accounts and devices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/BillLookup/History.aspx?LegSess=85R&amp;amp;Bill=HB2710&quot;&gt;HB 2710&lt;/a&gt;, providing that public records containing dates of birth can still be disclosed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/BillLookup/History.aspx?LegSess=85R&amp;amp;Bill=HB3581&quot;&gt;HB 3581&lt;/a&gt;, a helpful-sounding law requiring agencies to publish a data dictionary and instructions for using any databases that they disclose in response to a public records request, and also requiring them to provide more explanation of why it’s necessary to charge for programming work to fulfill a records request.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, on Tuesday, the House Homeland Security and Public Safety Committee &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/Committees/MeetingsUpcoming.aspx?Chamber=H&quot;&gt;will hold a public hearing&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/BillLookup/Actions.aspx?LegSess=85R&amp;amp;Bill=HB2044&quot;&gt;HB 2044&lt;/a&gt;, which includes some open records provisions among many other provisions relating to police misconduct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have an opinion about a bill that’s up for public hearing, testifying at the committee meeting is the best way to speak up! You just need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mytxlegis.legis.state.tx.us/hwrspublic/about.aspx&quot;&gt;register to testify (at the Capitol)&lt;/a&gt; and then say why you support or oppose the bill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Continue the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the #policy channel of the Open Austin community on Slack: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Get an invite&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
RSVP for our future events on Meetup: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/truthout/4039479403&quot;&gt;“Texas Justice” Photo Illustration&lt;/a&gt; by: Lance Page / t r u t h o u t; Adapted From: Alcately / Flickr) &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/&quot;&gt;(CC BY-NC-SA 2.0)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2017/04/22/lege-schedules-transparency-bills-for-public-hearings</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2017/04/22/lege-schedules-transparency-bills-for-public-hearings</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Government Under Debate in TX Legislature</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that more than 60 days have passed since the start of the Texas legislative session, we’re past the deadline for legislators to file non-emergency bills. Here’s a rundown of bills that could have an effect on transparency and open government this session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in contacting your legislators to support open data, you can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://openstates.org/find_your_legislator/&quot;&gt;openstates.org&lt;/a&gt; to find out whose districts you’re in and get their offices’ phone numbers. If you want to alert us to something we missed, or just join Open Austin’s discussion about policy, you can join the #policy channel in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Open Austin community on Slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bills-that-increase-openness-in-government&quot;&gt;Bills that increase openness in government&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openstates.org/tx/bills/85/HB2044/&quot;&gt;HB 2044&lt;/a&gt; (authored by Senfronia Thompson, pictured below) has openness provisions about traffic stops and police discipline records, as well as provisions dealing with police use of force in other ways. It’s supported by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.austinjustice.org/&quot;&gt;Austin Justice Coalition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/SenfroniaThompson.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Senfronia Thompson, author of HB 2044&quot; style=&quot;margin: auto; display: block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openstates.org/tx/bills/85/HB2596/&quot;&gt;HB 2596&lt;/a&gt;, among other things, would require home-rule municipalities to provide GIS files of its boundaries and extra-territorial jurisdiction. It would also require the production of a digital map to accompany annexation plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openstates.org/tx/bills/85/SB407/&quot;&gt;SB 407&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://openstates.org/tx/bills/85/HB792/&quot;&gt;HB 792&lt;/a&gt; would change the Public Information Act’s exception for contract bids, which contain competitive information. The bills would change the statute so that the exception didn’t apply once a contract was awarded. The Statesman published a Freedom of Information Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mystatesman.com/news/opinion/commentary-texas-must-repair-damage-public-information-act/5ZvyZur7pm5HEJqyzb8zDL/&quot;&gt;editorial strongly supporting these bills&lt;/a&gt;, which were introduced in response to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://caselaw.findlaw.com/tx-supreme-court/1705303.html&quot;&gt;Texas Supreme Court case called &lt;em&gt;Boeing v. Paxton&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The Texas Tribune &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.texastribune.org/2016/08/05/lawmakers-eye-monstrous-loophole-keeps-contract-de/&quot;&gt;wrote about the &lt;em&gt;Boeing&lt;/em&gt; decision&lt;/a&gt;, saying it prevented disclosures about Uber’s operations in Houston, among other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mystatesman.com/news/opinion/commentary-texas-must-repair-damage-public-information-act/5ZvyZur7pm5HEJqyzb8zDL/&quot;&gt;same editorial in the Statesman&lt;/a&gt; Kelley Shannon, executive director of the Freedom of Information Foundation of Texas, endorsed two other bills:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The Freedom of Information Foundation of Texas and other open government advocates are pressing for additional transparency measures in the Legislature. &lt;a href=&quot;https://openstates.org/tx/bills/85/HB2670/&quot;&gt;House Bill 2670&lt;/a&gt; attempts to improve access to public records stored in private email accounts and on private electronic devices. &lt;a href=&quot;https://openstates.org/tx/bills/85/HB2710/&quot;&gt;House Bill 2710&lt;/a&gt; seeks to resume access to dates of birth in certain public records, including crime documents and election filings, which fosters accuracy and informs the public.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openstates.org/tx/bills/85/HB793/&quot;&gt;HB 793&lt;/a&gt; would expand the definition of “governmental body” to particular contractors. This could include private entities that operate toll roads. According to the Statesman editorial, HB 793 would supersede the &lt;a href=&quot;http://caselaw.findlaw.com/tx-supreme-court/1706354.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Greater Houston Partnership&lt;/em&gt; Texas Supreme Court decision&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;a href=&quot;https://openstates.org/tx/bills/85/HB623/&quot;&gt;HB 623&lt;/a&gt; would require the creation of a web portal for state criminal justice data including reports submitted to the Attorney General.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bills-that-cut-back-on-open-government&quot;&gt;Bills that cut back on open government&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openstates.org/tx/bills/85/HB526/&quot;&gt;HB 526&lt;/a&gt; would amend the open-records statute to entitle only residents to public information. (Currently, anyone can submit a public-information request and governmental entities have a duty to fulfill them under the terms of the Government Code.) In addition to restricting the free flow of public information, this could be burdensome to both persons making requests and entities fulfilling them if the residence of the person requesting needs to be verified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openstates.org/tx/bills/85/HB1258/&quot;&gt;HB 1258&lt;/a&gt; would prevent anyone, including the state government, from allowing online public access to court records currently held by counties. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mystatesman.com/news/state--regional-govt--politics/texas-clerks-look-derail-web-based-public-access-court-records/pnNpmqoQlwe4s8xfBUZYbJ/&quot;&gt;state Office of Court Administration was planning on allowing access&lt;/a&gt; to the records through the state’s new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pacer.gov/&quot;&gt;PACER&lt;/a&gt;-like database called “re:SearchTX”. Even though the fees for the state database will be exorbitant at up to $6 per document, Chief Justice Hecht of the Texas Supreme Court thinks it will be an improvement for people who can’t afford a lawyer. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.texastribune.org/2017/03/09/seeing-turf-war-texas-counties-rally-against-statewide-records-portal/&quot;&gt;Texas Tribune quotes Hecht&lt;/a&gt; as saying “We’re talking about tens of thousands of people for whom getting a court record is probably impossible, at least practically…It’s just crucial. It’s important for transparency. The media and the public at large have a very fundamental interest in the public justice system.” A bill that blocks the state’s court record database from becoming available to the public will probably be a negative for open government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openstates.org/tx/bills/85/HB3107/&quot;&gt;HB 3107&lt;/a&gt; lets government bodies impose limits on the amount of records they’re required to disclose to a single requestor per month or year. The limits are determined by the amount of staff time used to produce the records, which creates the risk that governments will reduce their obligation to disclose records by using inefficient methods to produce the records. The limits don’t apply to employees of news organizations, but it could be burdensome for people with reasonable records requests to prove their requests are sponsored by a qualified organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Continue the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the Open Austin community on Slack: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Get an invite&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
RSVP for our future events on Meetup: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2017/03/19/open_government_under_debate_in_tx_legislature</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2017/03/19/open_government_under_debate_in_tx_legislature</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Announcement: Budget Party Awarded Mozilla Gigabit Community Fund Grant</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Austin Budget Party has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://learning.mozilla.org/blog/mozilla-awards-241000-to-explore-the-intersection-of-gigabit-technology-and-civics-robotics-farming-and-more&quot;&gt;awarded a Mozilla Gigabit Community Fund grant&lt;/a&gt; to help design and develop a Digital Mock City Council experience with &lt;a href=&quot;https://austinbudget.party/&quot;&gt;austinbudget.party&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of the grant is to create an online, open-source, digital budget debate platform and curriculum designed for middle and high school students to explore civic challenges and priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Austin contributors partnered with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cotmf.org/&quot;&gt;Capital of Texas Media Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, publisher of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.austinmonitor.com/&quot;&gt;Austin Monitor&lt;/a&gt;, to apply for this $15,000 award to improve the budget app, develop a teaching curriculum, and implement the program in 10 pilots schools in Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grant project builds on two existing initiatives:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Austin Budget Party is an open-source, mobile friendly, web app designed to engage the citizens of Austin over how city budgets are developed. Open Austin led the design and creation of this project through volunteer Civic Hack Nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cotmf.org/austinmonitorintheclassroom/&quot;&gt;Monitor in the Classroom&lt;/a&gt; offers local educators access to Austin Monitor content to create curriculum around current events and the practice of journalism. It is currently funded by Google Fiber’s Austin branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project will start as an educational pilot curriculum including participation from 10 different classrooms from each council district through a grant from the Mozilla Foundation. Each classroom will use austinbudget.party to craft a budget that meets the needs of their immediate community, elect a mock City Council representative from their peers, and learn about debate and formal proceedings. Then, the ten mock Council Members will create a digital quorum and run a meeting to be hosted over a gigabit powered video conferencing solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result of this will be a finalized budget that the students would present to the Austin City Council during the formal period of citizen feedback on the proposal annual budget. Conditional upon the success of this pilot, the end product would be a robust curriculum and platform that could scale so that hundreds of students would simultaneously collaborate and learn from their peers all over the City breaking down the barriers of economic segregation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using mobile technology solutions and high-speed internet connections, we aim to facilitate a realistic educational simulation where students learn by doing through mobile devices that meet them where they are in the digital world. Our team believes this type of learning experience can transform what has traditionally been possible in a classroom environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in following this project more closely or contributing yourself, visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/budgetparty&quot;&gt;project Github repo&lt;/a&gt; and join the &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;#budgetparty Slack channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Continue the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the Open Austin community on Slack: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Get an invite&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
RSVP for our future events on Meetup: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2017/02/08/budget-party-mozilla-gigabit-grant-announcement</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2017/02/08/budget-party-mozilla-gigabit-grant-announcement</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
