<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Austin - Code for America Brigade - Austin, Texas</title>
    <description>Open Austin is a volunteer citizen brigade advocating for open government, open data, and civic application development since 2009. We are an official brigade affiliated with the nonprofit Code for America which believes government can work for the people, by the people in the 21st century. Open Austin is focused on the needs of our own community and we use design, technology, and open data to improve the quality of life in our city.</description>
    <link>http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 05:10:21 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 05:10:21 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Uzbekistani delegation shares their experiences with open data on Austin visit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Last Tuesday, two Open Austinites attended a meeting with Uzbekistani leaders to discuss the topics of transparency and accountability in government. The meeting was organized by Global Austin, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.globalaustin.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;http://www.globalaustin.org/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; and the Uzbekistani leaders were in the US under the US Department of State’s International Visitor Leadership program, which fosters citizen diplomacy for emerging leaders. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://exchanges.state.gov/ivlp/ivlp.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;http://exchanges.state.gov/ivlp/ivlp.html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; The program’s organizers were interested in Open Austin’s work to bring citizens into active participation. Hailey Pate and Amalie Barras attended on behalf of the City of Austin and Open Austin, bringing insights about citizen engagement from inside the city and out. Also present, aside from the Uzbekistani IT and Telecom leaders, were journalists and translators, who simultaneously listened and interpreted between  English and Uzbekistani.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The meeting started off by focusing on the Uzbekistani open data portal, and providing a little context. Their data portal website &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.gov.uz/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;https://data.gov.uz/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; is well designed and thought-out, which Hailey and Amalie noted as an achievement in itself based on the fact that the target user is any citizen.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our participation in the initiative says a lot in itself. It is a legal base for reform,” one Uzbekistani leader shared. “In 2005 the government got to say what the state organizations should feature on their website.” He noted that in contrast, “in 2014 a law was passed on state organizations which requires that they highlight their activity via a website, and collect feedback. Citizens interested in engaging can connect with government organizations via their websites and now, quickly receive answers to questions.” Additionally, citizens have access to legal documents, and with the data portal, open government data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hailey asked whether it’d been difficult to develop user base for the data portal. The Uzbekistani leaders anticipated this challenge and developed and implemented a strategic plan for adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;They certainly have some great success stories. One Uzbekistani NGO that implemented a program using open data to distribute toddlers to day cares (which are state run).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;It shows the centers’ availability and reviews. They also have a technology similar to Open Austin’s very own &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://instabus.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Instabus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; app using GPS to track locations of their public transportation vehicles.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;One of the questions the Uzbekistani leaders had for Open Austin was how we deal with the legality and ethics of open data, and that’s a question we also have. Hailey shared  a couple of documents from the FCC &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://transition.fcc.gov/cgb/consumerfacts/cipa.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;http://transition.fcc.gov/cgb/consumerfacts/cipa.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; and Texas Attorney General &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.texasattorneygeneral.gov/files/og/PIA_handbook_2016.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;https://www.texasattorneygeneral.gov/files/og/PIA_handbook_2016.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; that are used as guidelines at the state and national levels. There is still much to be discussed, and in fact, in September the Uzbekistani leaders will devote a full week to a national summit with speakers and exhibitions around IT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The meeting ended on a high note with gratitude and gifts, including beautiful silk pashminas and an Uzbekistani document about open government in their country. Open Austin is grateful to have opportunities to share with folks tackling some of the same problems in other parts of the world. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 13:44:46 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/open%20data/open%20government/2016/02/27/uzbekistani-delegation-shares-their-experiences-with-open-data-on-austin-visit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/open%20data/open%20government/2016/02/27/uzbekistani-delegation-shares-their-experiences-with-open-data-on-austin-visit.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Open Data</category>
        
        <category>Open Government</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Code Across 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Sat, March 5, 2016&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 10:00 am – 4:00 pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; St. Edward&#39;s University, Munday Library - 3001 South Congress Avenue Austin, TX 78704 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/dir/30.234838,-97.7579789/30.231091,-97.757397/@30.2331063,-97.7608302,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m4!4m3!1m1!4e1!1m0&quot;&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The event is free, but seating is limited and advance registration is required:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/code-across-austin-2016-tickets-21752867412&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;REGISTER NOW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CodeAcross Austin 2016 &lt;/strong&gt;is an all-day event organized by Open Austin that starts off an arc of civic and social good projects through the rest of the year. The event will bring together nonprofit leaders, policy experts, civil servants, urbanists, community organizers, designers, developers, data scientists, and anyone with a passion to make our city better. Our goal is to launch a new wave of community-developed civic design &amp;amp; tech projects for continued work at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Civic Hack Nights&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; ATX Hack for Change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants will collaborate, brainstorm, and prototype around problems that affect Austin residents within a number of themes and community needs. The event will revolve around a facilitated workshop that utilizes human-centered design principles and agile design sprints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event is free and open to the public. It is conducted as part of the national “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codeforamerica.org/events/codeacross-2015/&quot;&gt;Code Across&lt;/a&gt;” weekend, sponsored by Code for America. “Code Across Austin” was launched in 2012 by visiting Code for America fellows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals for CodeAcross Austin: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Fully scoped &lt;strong&gt;problem statements&lt;/strong&gt; with actionable follow-up tasks. These problem statements will move along as projects in our year long arc of &quot;civic hacking&quot; with continued work at Open Austin Civic Hack Nights and at ATX Hack for Change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Identify &quot;Project Leaders&quot; who can champion community needs and lead implementation teams at ATX Hack for Change which will take place in June of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Foster dialogue between disparate networks in Austin including nonprofits, government staff, social good startups, and community organizations like Open Austin. Let&#39;s all work together on the hard problems in our city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; An interactive and enjoyable introduction to civic participation and innovative problem solving, aka &quot;civic hacking.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll explore themes such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Safety &amp;amp; Justice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health and Human services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Economic Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Transportation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communication and Engagement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Broadband and Digital Opportunities&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Sustainability&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning and Land Use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is it called CodeAcross?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CodeAcross is a weekend of civic hacking events hosted by groups like Open Austin throughout the world. The goal of CodeAcross is to activate the civic tech network and inspire residents everywhere to get actively involved in their communities. Though the title of this event is “CodeAcross&quot; to align with national events under the Code for America umbrella, we plan for this event to be focused on design thinking that is foundational to future project work which may or may not include “coding” projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This event is conducted under the Open Austin Code of Conduct: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/about/code-of-conduct&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.open-austin.org/about/code-of-conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read Last Years Recap &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.open-austin.org/article/1484&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parking and building map&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/screenshot20160220at11.23.22am.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-1720 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/assets/screenshot20160220at11.23.22am-1024x792.png&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot20160220at11.23.22am&quot; width=&quot;625&quot; height=&quot;483&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presented by &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/cropped-logo_OpenAustin_Color.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-1683 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/assets/cropped-logo_OpenAustin_Color-300x252.png&quot; alt=&quot;cropped-logo_OpenAustin_Color.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;252&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/logo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-1723 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/assets/logo-300x50.png&quot; alt=&quot;logo&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;50&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sponsored by&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/brigadelogo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-1724 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/assets/brigadelogo-300x111.png&quot; alt=&quot;brigadelogo&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;111&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/google.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-1725 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/assets/google-300x225.png&quot; alt=&quot;google&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 13:50:26 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/2016/02/21/code-across-2016.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/2016/02/21/code-across-2016.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Logo, Same Mission</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&#39;s 2016 and Open Austin is starting the year with a brand new logo.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the same mission and a more robust member base, Open Austin hopes to continue to grow and provide space for conversation and connection around civic tech and open government in Austin, Texas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why the Change?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/copy-Open_Austin_Banner_400x80.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-921&quot; src=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/assets//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/copy-Open_Austin_Banner_400x80.png&quot; alt=&quot;copy-Open_Austin_Banner_400x80.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;60&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our previous logo was designed by our volunteers and has served us well since it was introduced. It provided a symbol for members and supporters to rally under. It portrayed Open Austin as a group for coders and hackers with the open and closing tags, which is a common motif among Code for America brigades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we reexamined our goals and mission, we decided we could design something to better reflect the priorities of Open Austin to be &lt;strong&gt;an inclusive environment for all citizens&lt;/strong&gt; that want to work to &lt;strong&gt;make Austin better&lt;/strong&gt; using &lt;strong&gt;open data, design, and technology&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With new colors, we display the boldness, energy, and innovation that the organization fosters. With the new font, we mirror the friendly nature of our participants. And with the the new logo, we capture the diversity, enthusiasm, and professionalism of our organization. The star acknowledges our location in the capital city of lone star state. We include a closing bracket as a cornerstone component of the star, because coding is still an essential part of what we do. But it is not the only way our volunteers contribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want Open Austin to be open not only to self described programmers and hackers, but also to designers, data analysts, policy wonks, non-profit champions, social activists, public servants, students and normal citizens. Through our events, we want all our participants to realize their inner &quot;civic hacker,&quot; but we acknowledge that the term &quot;hacker&quot; can exclude people we intend to attract. Openness is essential to our mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are citizens working together to make a better Austin. And as we move forward we hope that you join us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View our logo redesign presentation below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: 1px solid #CCC; border-width: 1px; margin-bottom: 5px; max-width: 100%;&quot; src=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/jPqMBhkL7ldG1p&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 09:00:45 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/general%20news/2016/01/25/new-logo-same-mission.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/general%20news/2016/01/25/new-logo-same-mission.html</guid>
        
        <category>2016</category>
        
        <category>branding</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>new logo</category>
        
        <category>redesign</category>
        
        
        <category>General News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lightning Talks: Jan. 11 Open Gov &amp; Civic Tech Meetup Recap</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For Open Austin’s first meetup of the year, six members of our community presented rapid fire lightning talks showcasing the group’s diversity of skill and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subjects ranged from introductory to technical. Presentations covered everything from online legal resources, web mapping, satellite imagery APIs, problem framing, City of Austin open datasets, and updates to Open Records Policy from the 84th Texas Legislative Session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mscarey&quot;&gt;Matt Carey, OA Policy Lead&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/iced-coffee/files/88240/Law.on.Web.slides.pdf&quot;&gt;Free Law on the Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/prestonp&quot;&gt;Preston Pham&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://open-austin.github.io/leaflet-talk/&quot;&gt;Leaflet Primer: Developing with Open Source Web Maps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gusIreland&quot;&gt;Gus Ireland&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://gusireland.github.io/urthecast-api-presentation/&quot;&gt;Mapping with Urthecast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/atx_innovation&quot;&gt;Angela Hanson&lt;/a&gt;, Innovation Office - &lt;a href=&quot;https://prezi.com/hqtbt_jtme2y/innovation-method/&quot;&gt;Productive Brainstorming and Issue Framing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/spatialaustin&quot;&gt;John Clary&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/iced-coffee/files/88242/ACD.Presentation.To.Open.Austin.Jan.2016.pdf&quot;&gt;Austin Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/McCnnll&quot;&gt;Chris McConnell&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/iced-coffee/files/88241/OA_OpenRecordsInTexas.pptx&quot;&gt;Open Records In Texas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1QvCowZBzfkhN-rAjH4I0kYSBQZUGDTAj5ey1KiF-Ris/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Open Austin Announcements &amp;amp; Upcoming Events Deck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights from Twitter. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;Give us a follow to stay up to date.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://&amp;lt;blockquote%20class=&amp;quot;twitter-tweet&amp;quot; lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot; dir=&amp;quot;ltr&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;amp;quot;We ask why until we get to the root cause of problems.&amp;amp;quot; -&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/atx_innovation&amp;quot;&amp;gt;@atx_innovation&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/atx?src=hash&amp;quot;&amp;gt;#atx&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/CfaBrigade?src=hash&amp;quot;&amp;gt;#CfaBrigade&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/686729073666572289&amp;quot;&amp;gt;January 12, 2016&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script async src=&amp;quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&amp;quot; charset=&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;Meeting is starting now! #CfaBrigade&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://&amp;lt;blockquote%20class=&amp;quot;twitter-tweet&amp;quot; lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot; dir=&amp;quot;ltr&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;amp;quot;We ask why until we get to the root cause of problems.&amp;amp;quot; -&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/atx_innovation&amp;quot;&amp;gt;@atx_innovation&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/atx?src=hash&amp;quot;&amp;gt;#atx&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/CfaBrigade?src=hash&amp;quot;&amp;gt;#CfaBrigade&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/686729073666572289&amp;quot;&amp;gt;January 12, 2016&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script async src=&amp;quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&amp;quot; charset=&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;#opendata&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://&amp;lt;blockquote%20class=&amp;quot;twitter-tweet&amp;quot; lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot; dir=&amp;quot;ltr&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;amp;quot;We ask why until we get to the root cause of problems.&amp;amp;quot; -&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/atx_innovation&amp;quot;&amp;gt;@atx_innovation&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/atx?src=hash&amp;quot;&amp;gt;#atx&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/CfaBrigade?src=hash&amp;quot;&amp;gt;#CfaBrigade&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/686729073666572289&amp;quot;&amp;gt;January 12, 2016&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script async src=&amp;quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&amp;quot; charset=&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;#civictech&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://&amp;lt;blockquote%20class=&amp;quot;twitter-tweet&amp;quot; lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot; dir=&amp;quot;ltr&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;amp;quot;We ask why until we get to the root cause of problems.&amp;amp;quot; -&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/atx_innovation&amp;quot;&amp;gt;@atx_innovation&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/atx?src=hash&amp;quot;&amp;gt;#atx&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/CfaBrigade?src=hash&amp;quot;&amp;gt;#CfaBrigade&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/686729073666572289&amp;quot;&amp;gt;January 12, 2016&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script async src=&amp;quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&amp;quot; charset=&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;#atx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://&amp;lt;blockquote%20class=&amp;quot;twitter-tweet&amp;quot; lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot; dir=&amp;quot;ltr&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;amp;quot;We ask why until we get to the root cause of problems.&amp;amp;quot; -&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/atx_innovation&amp;quot;&amp;gt;@atx_innovation&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/atx?src=hash&amp;quot;&amp;gt;#atx&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/CfaBrigade?src=hash&amp;quot;&amp;gt;#CfaBrigade&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/686729073666572289&amp;quot;&amp;gt;January 12, 2016&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script async src=&amp;quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&amp;quot; charset=&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/fyjxiUIYsj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/686714664542060548&quot;&gt;January 12, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our new Policy Lead, Matt Carey gives a presentation on Free Law for Civic Apps. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/CfaBrigade?src=hash&quot;&gt;#CfaBrigade&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/atx?src=hash&quot;&gt;#atx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/opengov?src=hash&quot;&gt;#opengov&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/HdjzwOv04O&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/HdjzwOv04O&lt;/a&gt; — Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/686724898710933504&quot;&gt;January 12, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&quot;We ask why until we get to the root cause of problems.&quot; -&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/atx_innovation&quot;&gt;@atx_innovation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/atx?src=hash&quot;&gt;#atx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/CfaBrigade?src=hash&quot;&gt;#CfaBrigade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/686729073666572289&quot;&gt;January 12, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep up with our future events and join our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/events/227789488/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Meetup group to RSVP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Also feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/calendar&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;check out our calendar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ready to start working with us?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Join us on Slack now &lt;/a&gt;or check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/project-ideas&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Github Idea repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 12:45:53 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/2016/01/13/lightning-talks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/2016/01/13/lightning-talks.html</guid>
        
        <category>General News</category>
        
        <category>Open Austin Meetings</category>
        
        <category>City of Austin</category>
        
        <category>free law</category>
        
        <category>javasript</category>
        
        <category>leaflet.js</category>
        
        <category>online legal resources</category>
        
        <category>open datas</category>
        
        <category>problem framing</category>
        
        <category>satellite imagery APIs</category>
        
        <category>Texas Legislature</category>
        
        <category>web mapping</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ship It Weekend 2015 Event Summary</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The&amp;nbsp;goal for our first ever &lt;strong&gt;Ship It Weekend&lt;/strong&gt; was to
create a comfortable space for teams and new civic hackers&amp;nbsp;to push
forward&amp;nbsp;on existing projects. Our &lt;a href=
&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/668495254933368832/photo/1?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;
sponsors&lt;/a&gt; graciously provided fast wifi, good food, and coffee. All key
ingredients for productive civic hacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a summary of some of the achievements of our various projects over
the two day hack:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;.&lt;a href=
    &quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;@openaustin&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s &lt;a href=
    &quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ShipItAtx15?src=hash&quot;&gt;#ShipItAtx15&lt;/a&gt; is
    kicking off &lt;a href=
    &quot;https://twitter.com/CapitalFactory&quot;&gt;@CapitalFactory&lt;/a&gt; this morning!
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/CivicHack?src=hash&quot;&gt;#CivicHack&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/Hfm12iqXMV&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/Hfm12iqXMV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;— Austin Tech Live (@AustinTechLive) &lt;a href=
    &quot;https://twitter.com/AustinTechLive/status/668092999499390978&quot;&gt;November 21,
    2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;a href=
&quot;https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Austin,_TX/Buildings_Import&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open
Street Map (OSM) Import&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Team&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; split public
domain building data amongst 776 census block groups that represent&amp;nbsp;an
individual task (unit of work). They have now managed to finish 208 out of 776
tasks (about 25%).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So many Austin buildings imported into OSM this fine &lt;a href=
    &quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;@openaustin&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=
    &quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ShipItATX15?src=hash&quot;&gt;#ShipItATX15&lt;/a&gt;
    weekend. More than 25% done! &lt;a href=
    &quot;https://t.co/BY3c7wGRIG&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/BY3c7wGRIG&lt;/a&gt; — Andy Wilson
    (@wilsajj) &lt;a href=
    &quot;https://twitter.com/wilsajj/status/668561956207353856&quot;&gt;November 22,
    2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://open-austin.github.io/recycling-atx/&quot;&gt;Recycling
ATX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a webapp &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;for reporting
buildings that do not comply with Austin&#39;s Universal Recycling Ordinance.
They&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;extended the &lt;a href=
&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/recycling-bin&quot;&gt;backend API&lt;/a&gt; and made
progress on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/recycling-atx&quot;&gt;front
end&lt;/a&gt; of their app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.texasappleseed.org/&quot;&gt;Texas
Appleseed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;continued working on a &lt;a href=
&quot;https://openaustin.cartodb.com/u/oa-admin/viz/cb394812-8b56-11e5-91c0-0ecd1babdde5/public_map&quot;&gt;
map of discipline statistics by school districts in Texas&lt;/a&gt;. They worked on
making it easier to filter map views&amp;nbsp;on classroom removals and
the&amp;nbsp;use of school police and court to address student behavior. These map
visualizations are being included in their new School-to-Prison Pipeline
awareness website. The site is still under&amp;nbsp;development but can be viewed
on their &lt;a href=
&quot;http://forum-include.codio.io:3000/wordpress/?page_id=159&quot;&gt;demo host&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2015-11-29 at 11.06.40 PM&quot; class=&quot;post-inline-images&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/assets/Screen-Shot-2015-11-29-at-11.06.40-PM-167x300.png&quot; width=&quot;167&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=
&quot;http://open-austin.github.io/open-data-progress-report/&quot;&gt;Open Data Progress
Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; got an upgrade to display better on mobile browsers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=
&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/data-portal-analysis&quot;&gt;City of Austin Socrata
Data Portal Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Team is&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=
&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;building a program that fetches summary information from
the City’s open data portal and organizes it for analysis.
They&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;refactored their code so that other cities can use it, and
added a feature to fetch the list of resources from Socrata.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=
&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;As of right now, when you run the program, it generates a
csv with summary data from the data portal. View their program&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=
&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/data-portal-analysis&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://digitalatx.com&quot;&gt;Digital ATX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; team is
creating an inventory of programs and locations that offer computer labs and
training offerings. They&amp;nbsp;worked on some UI elements of the profile page,
and location inventory page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What a great team working in &lt;a href=
    &quot;https://t.co/YDwJwwL0WE&quot;&gt;https://t.co/YDwJwwL0WE&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;a href=
    &quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;@openaustin&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=
    &quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ShipItATX15?src=hash&quot;&gt;#ShipItATX15&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/XxyCSA6H7Z&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/XxyCSA6H7Z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;— COADigital Inclusion (@COADigInclusion) &lt;a href=
    &quot;https://twitter.com/COADigInclusion/status/668134373502246913&quot;&gt;November
    21, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2015-11-29 at 10.45.38 PM&quot; class=
&quot;post-inline-images&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=
&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/assets/Screen-Shot-2015-11-29-at-10.45.38-PM-161x300.png&quot;
width=&quot;161&quot;&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Transitime&lt;/strong&gt; team is m&lt;span style=
&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;aking the deployment of the &lt;a href=
&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/transitime-docker/blob/master/bin/fix_gtfs_stop_times.sh&quot;&gt;
OpenAustin Transitime fork&lt;/a&gt; more stable. They c&lt;/span&gt;reated a simple Bash
script to clean up the GTFS zip data provided by Capmetro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://instabus.org/&quot;&gt;Instabus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a webapp
that shows where buses are in Austin. The team worked to modernize the Instabus
code to use React, Immutable.js, and Redux. They also began a redesign of the
user interface to work better on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://austinparkequity.com/&quot;&gt;Austin Park
Equity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;aims to increase
equitable park access with maps thatt help visualize how Austin&#39;s park
resources are distributed throughout the City of Austin. The team w&lt;/span&gt;orked
on a &lt;a href=
&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/austin-park-equity/blob/4955183ef934e7bba23ad80374693a550dd88e29/scripts/census-reporter.js&quot;&gt;
node.js script&lt;/a&gt; to import census data from CensusReporter.org and thought
about data architecture to import park GIS data from a unified source (looking
at you Open Street Map) to pair better with Austin Green Map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Open Austin Policy Team&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;added some items to our
&lt;a href=
&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1SAwpRkuTDZamxTHlxL_WJlpJ573yRu36OR8cCExYxRg/edit&quot;&gt;
Google Doc&lt;/a&gt; of upcoming policy priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2015-11-29 at 10.52.16 PM&quot; class=
&quot;post-inline-images&quot; height=&quot;202&quot; src=
&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/assets/Screen-Shot-2015-11-29-at-10.52.16-PM-300x202.png&quot;
width=&quot;300&quot;&gt; The&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=
&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/iced-coffee/issues/2&quot;&gt;Open Austin
Logo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; design group created&amp;nbsp;a bunch&amp;nbsp;of doodles, sketches
and drafts&amp;nbsp;of a new OA logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://open-austin.github.io/&quot;&gt;Open
Austin Website Redesign&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;group worked on turning design
mockups into functioning templates for the header, homepage, blogs. They also
began content migration of existing OA articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks to everyone that came and participated at Ship It
Weekend!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Ship-it-group-photo.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=
&quot;Ship it group photo&quot; class=&quot;post-inline-images&quot; height=
&quot;225&quot; src=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/assets/Ship-it-group-photo-300x225.jpg&quot;
width=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Shoutout to our amazing sponsors! &lt;a href=
  &quot;https://twitter.com/codeforamerica&quot;&gt;@codeforamerica&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=
  &quot;https://twitter.com/CapitalFactory&quot;&gt;@CapitalFactory&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=
  &quot;https://twitter.com/Hired_HQ&quot;&gt;@Hired_HQ&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=
  &quot;https://twitter.com/USAA&quot;&gt;@USAA&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=
  &quot;https://twitter.com/Dell&quot;&gt;@Dell&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=
  &quot;https://twitter.com/BoozAllen&quot;&gt;@BoozAllen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=
  &quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ShipItATX15?src=hash&quot;&gt;#ShipItATX15&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/zLk9sWhmsI&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/zLk9sWhmsI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;— Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=
  &quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/668495254933368832&quot;&gt;November 22,
  2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View more photos from Ship It Weekend in our &lt;a href=
&quot;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.912559125486917.1073741829.412390968837071&amp;amp;type=3&amp;amp;uploaded=25&quot;
target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Facebook Album&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 12:00:55 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/2015/12/01/ship-it-weekend-2015-event-summary.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/2015/12/01/ship-it-weekend-2015-event-summary.html</guid>
        
        <category>Civic Hacking</category>
        
        <category>Hack Events</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ship It Weekend Nov 21st-22nd</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish the year strong at our Open Austin Ship It Weekend Hackathon, November 21st-22nd at Capital Factory!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: &lt;/strong&gt;Sat-Sun, November 21st-22nd 2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; Breakfast starts at 8:30am Saturday and kick-off is at 10:00am&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://capitalfactory.com/events/open-austin-finish-up-weekend/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Capital Factory&lt;/a&gt;, Austin Centre Executive Suites, 701 Brazos St, Austin, TX 78701 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/SYPmwf5d3zJ2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The event is free, but seating is limited and advance registration is required: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/open-austin-ship-it-weekend-tickets-19110607341&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;REGISTER NOW&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/strong&gt;Registration includes breakfast, lunch, and coffee for both days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All year, volunteers from Open Austin have been working on&lt;a title=&quot;Gihub issues&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/project-ideas&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt; Civic Tech projects&lt;/a&gt;. Needs in the community were identified and researched at the Code Across Austin event in February. Teams formed around projects at the City-sponsored ATX Hack for Change in June. And throughout the year, we&#39;ve hosted monthly Civic Hack Nights to push our projects forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Ship It Weekend is our final major event of the year!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;The focus will be on existing projects that just need that last little push.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All skills and experience levels are welcome.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Maybe you haven&#39;t done any &quot;civic hacking&quot; but you want to get involved with a project that could have a real impact in our community. We&#39;ll need help with design, development, user testing, field research, marketing, photography, writing, policy expertise and probably more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us as we push forward on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/project-ideas/issues&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;various projects &lt;/a&gt; that have been started throughout the year. Come celebrate a great year of civic hacking in Austin and let&#39;s Ship It!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This event is conducted under the Open Austin Code of Conduct: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/about/code-of-conduct&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.open-austin.org/about/code-of-conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/open-austin-ship-it-weekend-tickets-19110607341&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Register Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 21:26:43 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/2015/11/12/ship-it-weekend-nov-21st-22nd.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/2015/11/12/ship-it-weekend-nov-21st-22nd.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Code for America Summit Recap</title>
        <description>&lt;p id=&quot;ba92&quot; class=&quot;graf--p graf--first&quot;&gt;This month, 52 brigades and over 110 brigade captains and core team members from all across the world got together in Oakland, California for the 2015 Code for America Summit. Open Austin was represented by Brigade Captain, Mateo Clarke, and Delivery Lead, Luqmaan Dawoodjee. In addition to our brigade, the City&#39;s Innovation Office sent 18 Austin City staff to participate in the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;graf--p graf--first&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brigade Pre-Summit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;graf--p graf--first&quot;&gt;At the brigade Pre-Summit, Mateo gave an Ignite talk on the Austin Park Equity project and our year long &quot;Arc of Civic Hacking&quot;. The talk told the story of how a little bit of luck and deliberate year long planning can lead to successful hack projects. You can see the slides &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1C5aHuueb9PWr6cUSuhjEWvWBabIHPMrrI94t-W9SZik/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Luqmaan lead an unconference session and discussion on making projects easier to fork. Our brigade has been inspired by awesome projects in other cities but has found redeployment to be tricky. In response to this experience, we created a set of guidelines based on the unconference discussion: &lt;a class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/sporkability&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; data-href=&quot;/r/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Fopen-austin%2Fsporkability&quot;&gt;https://github.com/open-austin/sporkability&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code for America Announcements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;40e2&quot; class=&quot;graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Code for America as an organization is now 6 years old, and as they look to mature and consolidate their quick growth, they spoke a lot about sustainability and focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4e91&quot; class=&quot;graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;At the Pre-Summit, CfA introduced &lt;strong&gt;project stages&lt;/strong&gt; for brigade hack projects: Experiment, Alpha, Beta, and Official. Each of these stages is focused on getting user feedback:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;d76f&quot; class=&quot;graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Experiment&lt;/em&gt; — Listen to the community, research the problems, and conduct many experiments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;7d06&quot; class=&quot;graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alpha&lt;/em&gt; — Solve one person’s problem. Make project accessible for other contributors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;5111&quot; class=&quot;graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Beta&lt;/em&gt; — Get more users. Talk to users and get feedback. Write tests. Formalize a government, community or media partner for the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;126f&quot; class=&quot;graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Official&lt;/em&gt; — Host a launch party. Talk to more users. Focus on user accessibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;08e6&quot; class=&quot;graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;More information about these stages is available at &lt;a class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; href=&quot;http://www.codeforamerica.org/brigade/projects/stages&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; data-href=&quot;/r/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.codeforamerica.org%2Fbrigade%2Fprojects%2Fstages&quot;&gt;http://www.codeforamerica.org/brigade/projects/stages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;2782&quot; class=&quot;graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Code for America also announced four key &lt;strong&gt;practice areas&lt;/strong&gt; where they are hiring staff to grow subject matter expertise in each domain. Each of the Practice Area leads will help coordinate local brigade responses to global issues. These four domains are Health, Safety &amp;amp; Justice, Economic Development, and Communications &amp;amp; Engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common Themes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;b8ac&quot; class=&quot;graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In talking to other brigades, we noticed a common challenge faced by all brigades: how to integrate beginner programmers. Brigades are stretched thin building and maintaining their civic tech projects. How do we help people who come to hack nights who want to learn how to code? Many cities already have a rich ecosystem of learn to code meetups. Do we direct beginners to the &quot;learn to code&quot; meetups? Do we adapt our hack nights to be more educational? We talked to brigade leaders from Philadelphia who started an &lt;a href=&quot;http://technical.ly/philly/2015/09/10/open-source-mentorship-philadelphia-women/&quot;&gt;Open Source Mentorship Program&lt;/a&gt; specifically for women. Ultimately, we know that there are ways to contribute as a &quot;civic hacker&quot; in ways that don’t involve coding and many brigades are thinking about how to integrate human centered design methods into their projects that leverage softer skills of all participants and can lead to more refined hack projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Videos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;You can find videos of presentations from the Code for America Summit posted to Youtube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeforamerica.org/summit/&quot;&gt;https://www.codeforamerica.org/summit/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some of our favorite tweets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Remember you will meet the person that tried to fork your code at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/cfasummit?src=hash&quot;&gt;#cfasummit&lt;/a&gt; 😘! &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/g4c9fPdA8v&quot;&gt;https://t.co/g4c9fPdA8v&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/649007745706823680&quot;&gt;September 29, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join me &amp;amp; other Socrata users 4 a healthy, constructive discussion abt what should be next 4 data portals &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/cfasummit?src=hash&quot;&gt;#cfasummit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/dg5D0qcX5i&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/dg5D0qcX5i&lt;/a&gt; — Hailey Pate (@haileypate) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/haileypate/status/649291200474710017&quot;&gt;September 30, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MateoClarke&quot;&gt;@MateoClarke&lt;/a&gt; giving an ignite talk on &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/b3Y09aXYFQ&quot;&gt;http://t.co/b3Y09aXYFQ&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/cfasummit?src=hash&quot;&gt;#cfasummit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/cfabrigade?src=hash&quot;&gt;#cfabrigade&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/wQx8lC9fpS&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/wQx8lC9fpS&lt;/a&gt; — Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/648966019248058368&quot;&gt;September 29, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/SAYYAPHOTOBOOTH20151001_024411.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-1622 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/assets/SAYYAPHOTOBOOTH20151001_024411.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SAYYAPHOTOBOOTH20151001_024411&quot; width=&quot;788&quot; height=&quot;530&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 12:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/2015/10/21/code-for-america-summit-recap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/2015/10/21/code-for-america-summit-recap.html</guid>
        
        <category>Civic Hacking</category>
        
        <category>General News</category>
        
        <category>brigade</category>
        
        <category>code for america</category>
        
        <category>oakland</category>
        
        <category>summit</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SXSW Session Proposals of Interest</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2012, Code for America founder &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codeforamerica.org/blog/author/jen/&quot;&gt;Jen Pahlka&lt;/a&gt; was invited to to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sxsw.com/interactive&quot;&gt;SXSW Interactive&lt;/a&gt; give a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2401594,00.asp&quot;&gt;keynote address&lt;/a&gt;. Every year since, SXSW has presented many sessions of interest to the civic technology community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, SXSW is soliciting public input on session proposals through their &lt;a href=&quot;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/&quot;&gt;Panel Picker&lt;/a&gt; tool. You can vote a proposal up (or down) to show your support (or not), as well as leave comments. Registration is required, but it&#39;s free. Even if you haven&#39;t registered to attend the event, you can participate in the panel picker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;d like to highlight some of the sessions of interest that we know about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aug 30 update:&lt;/strong&gt; Innovation Office proposals added.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are aware of any additional session proposals that may be of interest to the local civic tech community, please email us at info@open-austin.org or tweet us at @OpenAustin. We&#39;ll post updates as warranted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Open Austin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each year for the past two years, Open Austin has hosted a meetup for open government hackers and civic technology enthusiasts. We&#39;d like to do it again this year. To support our proposal, please register for the SXSW Panel Picker and vote it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Civic Tech Hackers &amp;amp; Advocates Meetup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/55660&quot;&gt;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/55660&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Austin CityUP&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.austincityup.org/&quot;&gt;Austin CityUP&lt;/a&gt; is a new smart city consortium being formed. We are one of the founding members. There are a couple of interesting session proposals from CityUP participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Little Devices, Big Data, Smart Cities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/56682&quot;&gt;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/56682&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transportation and Mobility - The Austin Angle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/56757&quot;&gt;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/56757&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Digital Opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our friends at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://austintexas.gov/department/telecommunications&quot;&gt;City of Austin Office of Telecommunications and Regulatory Affairs&lt;/a&gt; have highlighted some panels focusing on digital divide and digital opportunities issues in the local community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empowering Low-Income Communities with Broadband&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/50791&quot;&gt;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/50791&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Austin: Leading the Way for Digital Inclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/52745&quot;&gt;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/52745&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlocking the Connection in Public Housing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/52802&quot;&gt;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/52802&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;US Mayors Technology &amp;amp; Innovation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The City of Austin Mayor&#39;s office participates in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://usmayors.org/innovation/pledge.htm&quot;&gt;US Conference of Mayors Technology and Innovation Task Force&lt;/a&gt;. They have offered some interesting session proposals relating to government and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cities: Innovation &amp;amp; Economic Engines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/56911&quot;&gt;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/56911&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tale of Two Cities: Challenging Urban Disparity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/56733&quot;&gt;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/56733&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cities 3.0: The Evolution of Smart Cities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/56776&quot;&gt;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/56776&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disrupt City: Government &amp;amp; Innovation Can Coexist&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/56886&quot;&gt;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/56886&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;City of Austin Innovation Office&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aug 30 update:&lt;/strong&gt; The following sessions have been proposed by the City of Austin Innovation Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lovable City: Scaling Human Connection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/49934&quot;&gt;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/49934&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Keeps Social Innovation from Scaling: Ego&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/56649&quot;&gt;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/56649&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the People by the People - the Human Algorithm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/57171&quot;&gt;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/57171&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prototyping Democracy: Better Collaboration Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/48724&quot;&gt;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/vote/48724&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 13:15:34 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/2015/08/25/sxsw-session-proposals-of-interest.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/2015/08/25/sxsw-session-proposals-of-interest.html</guid>
        
        <category>General News</category>
        
        <category>Open Government</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Smart Cities Meetup by CityUp, Aug 25</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Tue, Aug 25, 2015&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 5:30 - 7:30 PM&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Austin City Hall, 301 W 2nd St, 78701 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/N48jB&quot;&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free RSVP link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/smart-cities-meetup-using-technology-data-and-analytics-to-improve-cities-tickets-18154854659&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Open Austin is a member of the CityUP consortium, which is producing this event.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in meeting people who want to improve transportation, safety, health, education, economic opportunity, sustainability, environmental quality, and more by using technology, data, and analytics?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart city projects strive to advance all aspects of city life by using technology, data, and analytics to improve our understanding of urban design &amp;amp; planning, city infrastructure &amp;amp; operations, and civic issues &amp;amp; priorities. ‘Big Data’ is already transforming many industries and businesses, as well as education, research, and more. Smart city projects aim to collect data and use analytics to transform cities and the lives of the people in cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Austin CityUP™ is a new, comprehensive, city-wide consortium of companies, organizations, groups, and individuals that engage in smart city projects to advance Austin through digital technologies, data collection, analytics and modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in participating or just learning more, please join us for a smart city reception at Austin City Hall. You will hear about the upcoming plans of Austin CityUP™, learn about new opportunities, and meet people who are dedicated to transforming cities, and lives through the development, implementation, and operation of smart city projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone interested in advancing and improving Austin is welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy free snacks and drinks and bring your ideas and business cards!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 13:57:44 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/2015/08/17/smart-cities-meetup-by-cityup-aug-25.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/2015/08/17/smart-cities-meetup-by-cityup-aug-25.html</guid>
        
        <category>General News</category>
        
        <category>Public Meetings and Meetups</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Gov &amp; Civic Tech Meetup, Aug 17</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Mon, Aug 17, 2015&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 6:45 – 8:45 pm (program starts 7 pm)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Terrazas Branch Library, 1105 E. Cesar Chavez St, Austin, TX, 78702 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyurl.com/pgvzuw4&quot;&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invited Guests:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
• John Clary, &lt;a href=&quot;http://spatialaustin.com/&quot;&gt;Spatial Austin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
• Ryan Robinson, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.austintexas.gov/demographics&quot;&gt;City Demographer&lt;/a&gt;, City of Austin Planning and Zoning Department&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topic:&lt;/strong&gt; Austin&#39;s Demographic Trands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aug 18 update:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1zIH4s_3Ebp7QgFcW6zx1RoD50nnho9cMt3Q4dK_pFgQ/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Here are the slides&lt;/a&gt; from last night&#39;s update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;First, John Clary will share his work visualizing Austin’s 10-One Districts, growth, affordability, and gentrification with D3.js, OpenStreetMap, &amp;amp; Leaflet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, Austin&#39;s City Demographer will share his perspective on Austin Demographic trends and some interesting features of the new 10-One Council District demography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Austin hosts a monthly meet-up, to discuss local open government and civic technology issues. Our meet-ups are free and open to the public.  The meetup location is easily accessed by public transportation and has plentiful parking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 13:51:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/general%20news/open%20austin%20meetings/2015/08/17/open-gov-civic-tech-meetup-aug-17.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io/http://www.open-austin.org/general%20news/open%20austin%20meetings/2015/08/17/open-gov-civic-tech-meetup-aug-17.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>General News</category>
        
        <category>Open Austin Meetings</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
