<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Austin - Code for America Brigade - Austin, Texas</title>
    <description>Open Austin is a volunteer citizen brigade advocating for open government, open data, and civic application development since 2009. We are an official brigade affiliated with the nonprofit Code for America which believes government can work for the people, by the people in the 21st century. Open Austin is focused on the needs of our own community and we use design, technology, and open data to improve the quality of life in our city.</description>
    <link>http://open-austin.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://open-austin.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:49:47 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:49:47 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>2017: Our next challenge</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When Open Austin was founded in 2009, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/open&quot;&gt;Obama’s open data initiative&lt;/a&gt; was just getting started. In the eight years since, the world is now a different place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code for America &lt;a href=&quot;http://kut.org/post/what-can-code-america-do-austin&quot;&gt;announced it would send its Fellows&lt;/a&gt; to inject tech talent into local government, including Austin as a pilot city in 2012. Five years ago, the White House recognized the first weekend in June as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/06/03/open-data-and-innovation-national-day-civic-hacking-2016&quot;&gt;National Day of Civic Hacking&lt;/a&gt;, an event we co-present annually as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://atxhackforchange.org/&quot;&gt;ATX Hack for Change&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is interesting to juxtapose the history of Open Austin, and the larger national “Civic Tech” movement, with the Presidential Timeline. It reminds us just how young this work is. In 2017, our organization is experiencing it’s first Presidential Transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our 45th President, Donald J Trump, was inaugurated in DC last week. We’d like to reflect on highlights from 2016. Then we will lay out  our focus ahead for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;recap&quot;&gt;2016 Recap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;events&quot;&gt;Events&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We hosted or were invited to present at over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/open-austin/&quot;&gt;50 events&lt;/a&gt; including 17 Civic Hack Nights, 12 Civic Hack Saturdays, and 12 Open Gov &amp;amp; Civic Meetups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We co-presented the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.open-austin.org/blog/2016/06/07/Recap-ATX-Hack-for-Change-2016&quot;&gt;4th annual ATX Hack for Change&lt;/a&gt; hosted at St. Edward’s University.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We presented the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.open-austin.org/blog/2016/03/10/codeacross-austin-2016-recap&quot;&gt;6th Code Across Austin&lt;/a&gt; at St. Ed’s.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We hosted two seperate “Design for Civic Solutions” workshops in partnership with Austin Center for Design, Austin Design Week, and the City of Austin Office of Innovation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We listened to 16 Lightning Talks and read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.open-austin.org/blog/2016/06/07/Recap-ATX-Hack-for-Change-2016&quot;&gt;24 blogs posts&lt;/a&gt; presented and written by members of our increasingly diverse community.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We hosted a day long “Women Who Open Data” workshop co-presented with Women Who Code.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We co-presented two Game Nights themed around Budget &amp;amp; Transportation with Glasshouse Policy &amp;amp; the Austin Monitor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We raised $7,220 from our generous friends at data.world, Ordoro, Cloudera, Google Fiber, Mozilla Hive, Dev Bootcamp, Blue Treble, USAA, Austin B-cyle, HubCiti, Vizias, and Code for America.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;advocacy&quot;&gt;Advocacy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/19ipZ3_XVI6_k6K9EpRrV50rlq1RMGFzR9Z-RFG7Gnko/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Letter of Support&lt;/a&gt; and participated as a civil society partner in the City’s ongoing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opengovpartnership.org/node/8960&quot;&gt;OGP Subnational Government Pilot Program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our members collaborated to create a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1G-2yEphw1igKpaFQfSwPevWH3mMOACav9n-tDBViDro/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;2016 Advocacy Agenda&lt;/a&gt; with input from community&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We provided pre-RFP recommendations to CoA Clerk office on Council Meetings &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1FOLuCR6kRRTLQD5dyJCuIquRkEoaGi0aqAVlBFwVuPY/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Agenda Management System&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We continued our tradition of creating a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.open-austin.org/candidate-questionnaires/2016.html&quot;&gt;Council Candidate Survey&lt;/a&gt; and redesigned how the qualitative information is presented. Content from our 2016 City Council Candidate survey was included in &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/austin-tech-alliance/id1164265992?mt=8&quot;&gt;ATA mobile app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;projects&quot;&gt;Projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our community created &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/project-ideas/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=is%3Aissue%20created%3A2016-01-01..2016-12-31%20&quot;&gt;42 new project ideas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We updated our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.open-austin.org/blog/2016/01/25/new-logo-same-mission&quot;&gt;logo&lt;/a&gt; and launched a new website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Texas Appleseed gave us their Pro Bono Leadership Award at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://texasappleseed.org/good-apple-dinner&quot;&gt;Good Apple Dinner&lt;/a&gt; for our work on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.texasdisciplinelab.org/&quot;&gt;Texas School Discipline Lab&lt;/a&gt; helping to advocate for dismantling the school to prison pipeline.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our work in support of the Texas Criminal Justice Coalition, ACLU of Texas, and Texans for Accountable Government in creating &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.atxbodycam.com/&quot;&gt;atxbodycam.com&lt;/a&gt; was recognized on the main stage of the Code for America Summit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/iced-coffee/issues/130&quot;&gt;Civic Hack Canvas&lt;/a&gt; was forked and used in DC, Japan, and used by the City of Austin in a Transportation Grant challenge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;section&quot;&gt;2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the Election of Donald J. Trump, we’ve seen an increased hunger from our community for projects and advocacy work that promotes the civic good. We believe the intersection of technology &amp;amp; government are vital for progress in our experiment in democracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an all-volunteer organization, we labored to accomplish the achievements listed above. This year, we want to deepen our impact and try harder to support existing organizations in our community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to do this, our coreteam has chosen three internal projects and we’d like your help with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openaustin.typeform.com/to/zyE0a4&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apply here to join our coreteam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Membership Development Plan
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We want to make it easier for volunteers to assume roles within the organization, on projects, and in planning. We want to accommodate varying levels of availability.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We brainstormed about our org model and decided it looks most like a snowflake ❄️. We invite you to imagine where you could plug in.
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/snowflake_model_2017.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/snowflake_model_2017.png&quot; alt=&quot;Snowflake model of distributed leadership&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Values
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We know that if we want to fight hard battles in the next 4 years, we need to stand on a principled foundation.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;At our meetup in November 2016, we facilitated a collaborative design exercise to find language that describes the core values of Civic Tech.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Then we distilled these insights into a better reflection of Why we do our work.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The tangible outcome will be an updated About Page &lt;em&gt;(coming v soon)&lt;/em&gt;.
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/values_group_2016.png&quot; alt=&quot;Group working on asset mapping the resource of our organization&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/civic_tech_values_postit.png&quot; alt=&quot;An example of 6 values a group choose for Civic Tech&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/values_2017.png&quot; alt=&quot;Organizing different values to interpret meaning&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open Austin Labs
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We want to get better and support projects that have:&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Formal partnerships with external stakeholders (like other non-profits or the City of Austin)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Clear goals and deadlines&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Opportunities for funding via grants, contracts, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A plan for open-source maintenance and documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But most importantly, we want to remain a friendly community where people come to learn, share, and collaborate with each other. We will need your help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please consider joining our snowflake ❄️❄️❄️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openaustin.typeform.com/to/zyE0a4&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apply here to join our coreteam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;What does &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/democracy?src=hash&quot;&gt;#democracy&lt;/a&gt; look like? A full room of folks learning about &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/opendata?src=hash&quot;&gt;#opendata&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;@OpenAustin&lt;/a&gt;. Want to check it out? &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/6EdbVcV0bO&quot;&gt;https://t.co/6EdbVcV0bO&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/bQ6z9hNVy9&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/bQ6z9hNVy9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Daniel Ryne Lucio ⚡️ (@danielrynelucio) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/danielrynelucio/status/823711825942302720&quot;&gt;January 24, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~ Mateo Clarke, Brigade Captain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Continue the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the Open Austin community on Slack: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Get an invite&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
RSVP for our future events on Meetup: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2017/01/17/yearly-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2017/01/17/yearly-review</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Time to Back Up the Public&#39;s Climate Data</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With the Obama administration in its last weeks, the Washington Post reported &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/energy-environment/wp/2016/12/13/scientists-are-frantically-copying-u-s-climate-data-fearing-it-might-vanish-under-trump/&quot;&gt;“Scientists are frantically copying U.S. climate data, fearing it might vanish under Trump”&lt;/a&gt;. Especially if you have experience working with environmental data or policy, now is a good time to think about whether you’ve encountered any valuable climate or emissions datasets in danger of being swept away in the coming transition. Organizations like &lt;a href=&quot;https://ischool.utoronto.ca/content/guerrilla-archiving-event-saving-environmental-data-trump&quot;&gt;University of Toronto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ppehlab.org/datarefugefaqs&quot;&gt;University of Pennsylvania&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://climatemirror.org/&quot;&gt;climatemirror.org&lt;/a&gt; are creating archives to offer permanent mirrors for these climate datasets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datasets held by federal agencies aren’t the only ones that could be at risk. Environmental journalists recently noticed that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/endangered-species-under-gop-climate-change-information-on-the-web&quot;&gt;climate change information had been purged from a Wisconsin state government website&lt;/a&gt;. It’s worth protecting not just environmental information from federal agencies like the EPA and NOAA, but also state agencies like the &lt;a href=&quot;www.tceq.texas.gov&quot;&gt;Texas Commission on Environmental Quality&lt;/a&gt;, and even cities and counties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to find out whether a particular dataset is being backed up or what you can do to help, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://climatemirror.org/&quot;&gt;climatemirror.org&lt;/a&gt; for a list of existing mirrors and a Google Doc showing which datasets are in progress. Some tools for archiving government websites are available from climatemirror and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/edgi-govdata-archiving&quot;&gt;University of Toronto Github page&lt;/a&gt;. Alternatively, if your dataset is hotter than Texas in 2050 under a business-as-usual emissions projection, maybe you’d prefer to tell archivists about it privately. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://envirodatagov.org/&quot;&gt;Environmental Data &amp;amp; Governance Initiative&lt;/a&gt; is soliciting help accessing “environmental data that is not freely available on the web” via its encrypted email address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in a more local dataset that’s outside the scope of the mirroring projects listed here, or if you have a plan to create something with the data beyond just backing it up, consider bringing your project idea to Open Austin. You can submit your idea as an issue on our Github group’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/project-ideas/issues&quot;&gt;project-ideas page&lt;/a&gt; or look for collaborators at one of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;Civic Hack Nights&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Austin can also be a resource for environmental data consumers who want to encourage governments to release new datasets, or to keep their existing data more timely or accessible. Contact us on the #policy channel of our &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Slack group&lt;/a&gt; if you have an issue you’d like to add to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.open-austin.org/advocacy/&quot;&gt;advocacy agenda&lt;/a&gt; for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Continue the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the Open Austin community on Slack: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Get an invite&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
RSVP for our future events on Meetup: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2017/01/08/time-to-back-up-the-publics-climate-data</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2017/01/08/time-to-back-up-the-publics-climate-data</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Austin Honored with Pro Bono Leadership Award from Texas Appleseed</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Many Texans see the evidence of the school-to-prison pipeline in their daily lives – sometimes because a video goes viral or because they are a parent, grandparent, or advocate for a child they love. Texas Appleseed has long been involved in working to address systemic problems related to zero-tolerance school disciplinary policies and hostile school climates – and they wanted a new forum to reach people and expand the dialogue around the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://texasappleseed.org/&quot;&gt;Texas Appleseed&lt;/a&gt; is a public interest justice center. This nonprofit works to change unjust laws and policies that prevent Texans from realizing their full potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Texas Appleseed approached us at Open Austin with the idea to create a website that would bring together advocates, students, parents, and educators in Texas who are interested in improving educational opportunities and outcomes for youth. Our volunteers stepped up to help, donating more than a year of pro bono time by building a new website, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.texasdisciplinelab.org/&quot;&gt;Texas School Discipline Lab&lt;/a&gt;, from scratch. Volunteers also designed and gathered data for several &lt;a href=&quot;https://txappleseed.github.io/txappleseedmap/&quot;&gt;interactive maps&lt;/a&gt; that feature discipline data from over 1,200 school districts across Texas, while offering their expertise on the best way to present data that would make it easy to understand, visually appealing, and accessible to various audiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/good-apple-dinner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Good Apple Dinner program header&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, November 17, Open Austin representatives were presented with the &lt;em&gt;Pro Bono Leadership Award&lt;/em&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://texasappleseed.org/good-apple-dinner&quot;&gt;Texas Appleseed’s 20th Annual Good Apple Dinner&lt;/a&gt;. Open Austin is honored to support Texas Appleseed in one small aspect of this important work that will improve the lives of children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source Code for the School District Discipline Maps can be found on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/txappleseed/txappleseedmap&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contributors to this project include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Patricia Silva&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;John Tyree&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carissa Melanson&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Harold Jackson&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Diego Hernandez&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Michelle Schulze&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Matt Carey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;David Infortunio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yamanda Wright&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mateo Clarke&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;and many more&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/11/18/texas-appleseed-pro-bono-leadership-award</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/11/18/texas-appleseed-pro-bono-leadership-award</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>October Open Gov &amp; Civic Tech Meetup Recap - Election Themed Lightning Talks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For our pre-election Open Gov &amp;amp; Civic Tech Meetup, we had five community members give 10 minute lightning talks on different topics under the theme of elections and voting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View the the slides from their talks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Matt Carey &amp;amp; Mateo Clarke, Open Austin - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/iced-coffee/files/540541/city_council_2016_survey.1.pdf&quot;&gt;2016 City Council Candidate Surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tommy Miller, Travis County, GIS Coordinator - &lt;a href=&quot;http://tcto.maps.arcgis.com/apps/Minimalist/index.html?appid=c181a61d343b4645aa7c1c3cd445aff6&quot;&gt;Voting Wait Times &amp;amp; Polling Locations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shellee O’Brien - &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1bewoqrAtTIiToKOZlyGsjCSAc8pIGhM-hwVrsc4J-KE/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;“The Problem with Lazy, Apathetic Non-Voters”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mina Adame &amp;amp; Dario Fidanza, Ideation League - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/DarioFidanza/affecting-civic-space-with-ux-design&quot;&gt;Affecting Civic Spaces with UX Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ed Ireson, FOMO ATX - &lt;a href=&quot;https://fomo.vote/&quot;&gt;FOMO.vote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights from Twitter. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;Give us a follow to stay up to date.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Tommy Miller, Travis County GIS coordinator presents voting wait times &amp;amp; polling location on a GIS map. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/ebWi3Yr6dr&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/ebWi3Yr6dr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/788178647815327744&quot;&gt;October 18, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;What do nonvoters care about? Impact, convenience, and community, says &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stepwinder&quot;&gt;@stepwinder&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;@openaustin&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/civictech?src=hash&quot;&gt;#civictech&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/65uLcD5KHv&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/65uLcD5KHv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Tom O&amp;#39;Connell (@mrtomocon) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mrtomocon/status/788184254089867264&quot;&gt;October 18, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;ED Ireson talks About the inception of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/FOMOvote&quot;&gt;@FOMOvote&lt;/a&gt; ! 🙌🏼&lt;br /&gt;🗳&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/civictech?src=hash&quot;&gt;#civictech&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/atx?src=hash&quot;&gt;#atx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/BK7fXkNGAg&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/BK7fXkNGAg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/788189054353354752&quot;&gt;October 18, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;We have a system error not an individual error when it comes to non-voters.&amp;quot; 👏🏽 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stepwinder&quot;&gt;@stepwinder&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;@openaustin&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/GetouttheVote?src=hash&quot;&gt;#GetouttheVote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Vickie (@Victoria_ODell) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Victoria_ODell/status/788182114751569920&quot;&gt;October 18, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ideationleague&quot;&gt;@ideationleague&lt;/a&gt; presenting a lightning talk at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;@openaustin&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mina_adame&quot;&gt;@mina_adame&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/openaustin?src=hash&quot;&gt;#openaustin&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/latino?src=hash&quot;&gt;#latino&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/vote?src=hash&quot;&gt;#vote&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/Z5XhkRljL1&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/Z5XhkRljL1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dario (@ArtAwake) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ArtAwake/status/788220424140185600&quot;&gt;October 18, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Continue the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the Open Austin community on Slack: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Get an invite&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
RSVP for our future events on Meetup: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/10/19/october-meetup-recap</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/10/19/october-meetup-recap</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>September Open Gov &amp; Civic Tech Meetup Recap-Data.World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/events/233380715/&quot;&gt;Monday’s Open Government and Civic Technology meetup&lt;/a&gt; had 2 guest speakers present. Doug Matthews, Chief Communication Officer, covered the state of the community registry. Jonathan Ortiz, Data Scientist and Knowledge Engineer at Data.world, spoke on the startup, his census project, and linked data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Getting started! 🙌🏼 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/OmIGqIydo5&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/OmIGqIydo5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/778021336891346945&quot;&gt;September 20, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;community-registry-an-unexpected-journey&quot;&gt;Community Registry: an Unexpected Journey&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doug Matthews started the meeting by outlining the current state of the &lt;a href=&quot;assets/documents/community_registry_pitch.pdf&quot;&gt;Austin Community Registry&lt;/a&gt;. As described by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.austintexas.gov/page/community-registry-search&quot;&gt;data.gov&lt;/a&gt;—a community registry is a tool that allows for “neighborhoods and others to be notified of issues relating to their area”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Kicking off the Convo on a community registry. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/civictech?src=hash&quot;&gt;#civictech&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/7jYjw0oKvF&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/7jYjw0oKvF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/778028797610176512&quot;&gt;September 20, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthews highlighted the current complexities of filling out the Austin registry and keeping it up to date. His slide examples showed how time consuming and frustrating current processes are. It is clear that a better and more interactive solution is needed. Streamlining the registry application and giving it more interactive capabilities would increase the value and functionality of this important community resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this, Google Fiber and the city are partnering up to push this project forward and find help to create the best solution for Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of challenges and opportunities in working on the community registry. You can get engaged and help tackle them by checking out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/project-ideas/issues/78&quot;&gt;open project issue on github&lt;/a&gt; or reaching out to Doug by emailing douglas.matthews@austintexas.gov.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/documents/community_registry_pitch.pdf&quot;&gt;View and Download Doug Matthews slides.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-data-wants-to-be-linked&quot;&gt;Open Data Wants to Be Linked&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night concluded with Jonathan Ortiz, a data scientist from &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.world/&quot;&gt;Data.world&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data.world is a public benefit company working to break down the barriers between data and people. Unlike some companies, they’re not about the visualization or analysis of data. They’re about helping people find the data they need and enabling cross-collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jonathan highlighted the sentiment that Data.world is about more than data though. He said, “It’s about making understanding easier”.  He also emphasized the benefits of social sharing and data by saying,” We should work together. We should collaborate. We should not duplicate our efforts”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He continued to explain that a lot of the data, though open and available, is being stood up and posted in silos. This means that other people can’t access it and might not even know about its existence. Having access to more relevant data could allow for more thorough research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Data providers are disconnected from data users. They load it in and you pull it out.&amp;quot;  - Jonathon Ortiz of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/datadotworld&quot;&gt;@datadotworld&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/z16mIT9iVs&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/z16mIT9iVs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/778046012560510976&quot;&gt;September 20, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a social platform isn’t the only way to share data though. Linked data holds many possibilites and it’s something the folks at Data.world are working on. &lt;a href=&quot;http://linkeddata.org/&quot;&gt;Linked data&lt;/a&gt; is what makes up the semantic web, which is also sometimes called a Research Description Framework or RDF. When you upload your data to Data.world there is the opportunity to link it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linking data joins the data sets to others by following a set data model. This enables the data to be better understood by machines and thus allows users to discover more insights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the linked data technology, Jonathan and Data.world partnered with the US Census Bureau. They aim to help data users by enriching the analyses that need US demographic information. They are doing this by working to ingest the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.census.gov/programs-surveys/acs/&quot;&gt;American Community Survey&lt;/a&gt; in a linked data format. The project is ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get an invite for Data.world and share some of your own data sets by visiting the following link: [https://data.world/preview-signup]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/documents/linked-data-presentation.pdf&quot;&gt;View and download the full presentation that Jonathan gave.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Continue the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the Open Austin community on Slack: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Get an invite&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
RSVP for our future events on Meetup: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/09/25/september-meetup-recap</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/09/25/september-meetup-recap</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>August Open Gov &amp; Civic Tech Meetup Recap-Transportation &amp; Sensors</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;ut-center-for-transportation-research&quot;&gt;UT Center for Transportation Research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our August meeting we invited Jen Duthie (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jenduthie?lang=en&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;) &amp;amp; Itamar Gal, from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ctr.utexas.edu/&quot;&gt;UT Center for Transportation Research Network Modeling Center&lt;/a&gt; to speak about recent initiatives utilizing Austin Transportation Department sensor data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Dr. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jenduthie&quot;&gt;@JenDuthie&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; Itamar Gal of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CTRUTAustin&quot;&gt;@CTRUTAustin&lt;/a&gt; describe the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/transportation?src=hash&quot;&gt;#transportation&lt;/a&gt; Data Rodeo concept to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;@openaustin&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/ZEdVgDsPFh&quot;&gt;https://t.co/ZEdVgDsPFh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Steven Polunsky (@StevenPolunsky) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/StevenPolunsky/status/765347403230621697&quot;&gt;August 16, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;connecting-the-data&quot;&gt;Connecting the Data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duthie shared some of the difficulties in knowing who is collecting what transit data and what tools there are using to understand and share it. Duthie said “the gap [for collaboration] is so big and it doesn’t really need to be there.” She highlighted the need “to cut through the red tape” and make transportation data more accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this UTCTR is working on &lt;a href=&quot;datarodeo.org&quot;&gt;Data Rodeo&lt;/a&gt;. The idea for Data Rodeo came out the City of Austin’s bid for the Department of Transportation  &lt;a href=&quot;http://kxan.com/2016/06/21/austin-loses-out-on-50-million-smart-city-bid/&quot;&gt;Smart Cities grant&lt;/a&gt; that was ultimately awarded to Pittsburg. It focuses on the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Access to data &amp;amp; Tool&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Innovation &amp;amp; Collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data centric research &amp;amp; Learning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enabling Smart Cities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Getting access to data is slow but we are making huge strides&amp;quot; - Jen Duthie from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CTRUTAustin&quot;&gt;@CTRUTAustin&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/2tsIEdkuzH&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/2tsIEdkuzH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/765348647114465280&quot;&gt;August 16, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sensors&quot;&gt;Sensors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Itamar Gal finished out the the presentation. He stated that although collecting transportation data and collaboration are great, they’re not necessarily a city priority right now. Though this is true, the city currently has sensors that are collecting data at many intersections. He challenged the group to find uses for the data to help push interest and investment in the sensors and data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Itamar shows a map where current static bluetooth sensors are located in the city. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/eYM3a9e3jf&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/eYM3a9e3jf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/765351053193728002&quot;&gt;August 16, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Itamar showed the group a map that shows all the Bluetooth sensors that the city has. The current Bluetooth sensors are field sensor devices and sit statically at intersections or near them. The Bluetooth sensors look for devices with active Bluetooth (which could be pedestrians, cyclists, cars with Bluetooth-enabled stereo). When an active Bluetooth device is nearby, the sensor logs the time, the location of the sensor, and a hash of the device’s MAC address. Using the hashed MAC address, you could track a device as it travels between sensors to get an idea of the travel time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The radar sensors have the potential to be more useful than the Bluetooth sensors because it could not only detect pedestrians, cyclists, and cars without active Bluetooth devices, but could also measure their speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After displaying the data, Itamar highlighted that it would be great to expand the network. Jen Pointed out the city is struggling between starting and maintaining the own network or paying for subscription of data from other entities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Itamar concluded with am animated heatmap of the bluetooth sensor reading throughout the day with CardoDB. He believes the community could do interesting things with the data. Jen said that “we put out our reports and show our story but want to give other people the chance to let other stories emerge.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get involved, give feedback, or ask questions then you can email Jen Duthie, Ph.D., PE at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#106;&amp;#100;&amp;#117;&amp;#116;&amp;#104;&amp;#105;&amp;#101;&amp;#064;&amp;#117;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#120;&amp;#097;&amp;#115;&amp;#046;&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#117;&quot;&gt;&amp;#106;&amp;#100;&amp;#117;&amp;#116;&amp;#104;&amp;#105;&amp;#101;&amp;#064;&amp;#117;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#120;&amp;#097;&amp;#115;&amp;#046;&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#117;&lt;/a&gt; or Itamar Gal, Ph.D. at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#105;&amp;#103;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#064;&amp;#117;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#120;&amp;#097;&amp;#115;&amp;#046;&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#117;&quot;&gt;&amp;#105;&amp;#103;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#064;&amp;#117;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#120;&amp;#097;&amp;#115;&amp;#046;&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#117;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;presentation-slides&quot;&gt;Presentation Slides&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/documents/CTR_OpenAustin_081516.pdf&quot;&gt;Center for Transportation Research Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1_ZxJEOcp_P1PYRp-fbb82GPT6YiTbn90X5nUb8RAox4/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Open Austin General Announcement Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Continue the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the Open Austin community on Slack: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Get an invite&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
RSVP for our future events on Meetup: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/09/12/aug-meetup-recap</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/09/12/aug-meetup-recap</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>July Open Gov &amp; Civic Tech Meetup Recap-Hacking the Budget</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month Open Austin had a unique lineup of speakers. Our topic was Hacking the budget and we had Grace Miller with GlassHouse policy explain how the city budget can be influenced by the community. We also had Brandon Latham-Jones the outreach Director for District 4, Kerry O’Connor from the Innovation Office, and Robert Friedman from the Mozilla Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Hanging out at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;@openaustin&lt;/a&gt;, listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kerry_atx&quot;&gt;@kerry_atx&lt;/a&gt; and folks talk about open gov, budgeting and hacking. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/atx?src=hash&quot;&gt;#atx&lt;/a&gt; 🖥💡 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/rEZDToVA6G&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/rEZDToVA6G&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Daniel Ryne Lucio ⚡️ (@danielrynelucio) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/danielrynelucio/status/755206939399684096&quot;&gt;July 19, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;budget-breakdown&quot;&gt;Budget Breakdown&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grace Atkins from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glasshousepolicy.org/&quot;&gt;Glasshouse Policy&lt;/a&gt; gave a presentation on why education around city budgeting is necessary. Glasshouse policy is a think tank in Austin that works to engage the general public around public policy. They help to create a more responsive and representative government. They notice that critical decisions are being made at the local level and wants others to understand and engage with those decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1xwLwHwfC9cOOSTbM4R2vsFQ_FgT9sdQWJ8UTS_zUT54/edit#slide=id.g151ddb760f_0_6&#39;&quot;&gt;View and/or download the presentation&lt;/a&gt; that Grace gave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;We&#39;ve partnered with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/austinmonitor&quot;&gt;@austinmonitor&lt;/a&gt; on an exciting new project! Find out more here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/Mj9EVyvSMw&quot;&gt;https://t.co/Mj9EVyvSMw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Glasshouse Policy (@OpenPolicyTx) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/OpenPolicyTx/status/755059943653253120&quot;&gt;July 18, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-the-budget&quot;&gt;Why the Budget?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grace said that decisions around city spending aren’t just big, vague, and ignorable. City spending decisions impact our daily lives and go largely unnoticed due to inaccessibility to the general public. To breakdown barriers for understanding the budget, Grace pointed out that we have to be engaged and learning both in-person and online&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;working-to-gamify-the-budget&quot;&gt;Working to Gamify the budget&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind Glasshouse Policy and Austin Monitor have teamed up for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/budget-game-night-tickets-26423729085&quot;&gt;budget game night that’s happening tomorrow&lt;/a&gt;, August 16th at 6:00pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.austinmonitor.com/&quot;&gt;Austin Monitor&lt;/a&gt; is a locally focused government reporting website. They wants to provide locals with a clear picture of what is going on in Austin. They do this by reporting in an intentionally neutral tone that helps readers make their own judgments on local politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They believe that by collaborating to gamify the budget they can help folks understand where and how city money is spent and where it comes from. This is just one step to allowing more people to get involved and influence decisions that go into make the city budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past involvment with volunteers, notably the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.budgetboxapp.com/welcome&quot;&gt;Budget-in-a-Box&lt;/a&gt; app, has made the City of Austin rethink how they present the budget and continued engagement. Currently the city has a different budgeting platform for citizen engagement, &lt;a href=&quot;https://austintx.budgetsimulator.com/&quot;&gt;Dollars &amp;amp; Sense&lt;/a&gt;. Though similar to Budget-in-a Box, Dollars &amp;amp; Sense prompts users to enter home value. An action that the rest of the experience then relies on to illustrate tax and utility bill changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game night and newest iteration of a budgeting app that Open Austin is helping to build, ensure that the conversation around participatory budgeting and citizen engagement continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mozilla-gigabit-community-fund&quot;&gt;Mozilla Gigabit Community Fund&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Friedman came to introduce &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/gigabit/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Gigabit Community Fund&lt;/a&gt; to the community. Friedman said that Mozilla was in town to take advantage of the Google Fiber network in Austin. They hope to Build and fund educational resources that use gigabyte speed connections to advance learning opportunity for young people, explore big data, synchronized collaboration, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in developing in the education sphere then Mozilla has a fund allocated for prototyping and growing projects out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information contact Robert Friedman via email at robert@mozillafoundation.org&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-government-partnership-update&quot;&gt;Open Government Partnership Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kerry O’Connor from the Innovation Office gave us an update on the Open Gov Partnership that the city accepted earlier this year. Kerry informed the group that we are the only U.S city apart of a subnational pilot program for Open Government and the program currently has us paired with Ireland with whom we support and share knowledge with. Open Austin, Leadership Austin, Vision Zero ATX, and the City of Austin are helping push this program forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;This isn&amp;#39;t an imagine Austin kind of thing. This is an implement Austin kind of thing&amp;quot;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kerry_atx&quot;&gt;@kerry_atx&lt;/a&gt; on the Open Government Partnership&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/755202029467893760&quot;&gt;July 19, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the partnership the city not only declare its commitments for being more open, it is also held more accountable. Austin have 1 year to put in place any commitments that we come up with and they must be co-created with civil society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityofaustin.github.io/open-gov-partnership/&quot;&gt;ATX Hack for Change a site was launched&lt;/a&gt; for the campaign and currently the team needs some help updating it among other task for their campaign to commitment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in getting involved there is an [OpenGov channel in the Open Austin Slack]
(https://open-austin.slack.com/messages/opengovpartnership/) where you can ask questions and engage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1sWrJSMndCjpB4cJy8IVRB7km4PsTrz6ue74wrj_dYEg/edit#slide=id.g15df7ec05d_0_11&quot;&gt;Kerry’s Full Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;direct-democracy&quot;&gt;Direct Democracy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Braden Latham-Jones- D4 Outreach Director gave a quick presentation on budgeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Braden explained our strong manager, weak mayor system in Austin and described how the manager purposes a budget to city council that is then amended and improved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Continue the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the Open Austin community on Slack: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Get an invite&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
RSVP for our future events on Meetup: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/08/15/july-meetup-recap</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/08/15/july-meetup-recap</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>June Open Gov &amp; Civic Tech Meetup Recap - Lightning Talks </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For this month’s Open Gov &amp;amp; Civic Tech Meetup, we had five community members give 10 minute lightning talks on a range of topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From data portals to GeoJason our presenters introduces both non-technical and technical presentations to a full room. View the the slides from their talks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/paulserraino&quot;&gt;Paul Serraino&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulserraino.com/geojson-talk/#/Law.on.Web.slides.pdf&quot;&gt;GeoJason + React + Leaflet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dhernandex&quot;&gt;Diego Hernandez&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://dhernandex.github.io/sass-color-functions/presentation/#/&quot;&gt;The Power of Sass Color Functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nikolac88&quot;&gt;Nik Collins&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://commute.ly/#!/&quot;&gt;Commute.ly&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/iced-coffee/files/324749/commutely-austin-open.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Victoria_ODell&quot;&gt;Victoria O’Dell&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1F0jLB3vJsLLRAXzVwLVB0cr0PGwm_2h33GQquZHzkR0/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Permitting Application Wizard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AmalieBarras&quot;&gt;Amalie Barras&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/iced-coffee/files/324766/PANDA.Lightnin.pdf&quot;&gt;Community Data Portal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1aJPnMyh-PBQ0HTfA1dNPRzrZT2949-P5ww5U_2Tab6U/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Open Austin Announcements &amp;amp; Upcoming Events Deck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights from Twitter. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;Give us a follow to stay up to date.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AmalieBarras&quot;&gt;@AmalieBarras&lt;/a&gt; talking about building an open data portal for Austin at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin&quot;&gt;@openaustin&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/jkan?src=hash&quot;&gt;#jkan&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/cHyk4nmMuo&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/cHyk4nmMuo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; luqmaan (@luqmonster) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/luqmonster/status/745067741388800000&quot;&gt;June 21, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;fr&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Nik Collins introduces commute.ly &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/GskOls1OG0&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/GskOls1OG0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/745063606681669633&quot;&gt;June 21, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Diego starts his presentation on Sass color functions. 🎨 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/UT4ZW0F6xZ&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/UT4ZW0F6xZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/745057664422445056&quot;&gt;June 21, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Standards leads to accessibility &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/YFG0L4TytN&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/YFG0L4TytN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Open Austin (@openaustin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin/status/745055519904169984&quot;&gt;June 21, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Continue the Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the Open Austin community on Slack: &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.open-austin.org/&quot;&gt;Get an invite&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
RSVP for our future events on Meetup: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Open-Austin/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openaustin?lang=en&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Open-Austin-412390968837071/&quot;&gt;Like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/06/23/lightning-talk-recap</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/06/23/lightning-talk-recap</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quantifying Austin&#39;s Housing Supply</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Austin has a serious problem with access to affordable housing. And &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lao.ca.gov/Publications/Report/3345&quot;&gt;some research indicates&lt;/a&gt; that increasing the supply of housing can help prevent displacement of lower-income residents from urban areas, even if it’s market-rate housing and not part of an affordable housing program. Researchers in Austin are interested in learning about how the city’s housing supply has changed, and about how those changes have affected the fortunes of individual neighborhoods. Unfortunately, it’s hard to answer that question with the data the city currently releases to the public. A few months ago the city released &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.austintexas.gov/Permitting/Issued-Construction-Permits/3syk-w9eu&quot;&gt;decades of historical building permits on its data portal&lt;/a&gt;, and even more up-to-date records can be found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/construction-permits&quot;&gt;Open Austin’s Github repository&lt;/a&gt;, but there’s still no clear way to see how many housing units have been demolished or created as a result of each building permit the city issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A glance at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.austintexas.gov/page/building-applications&quot;&gt;Austin’s building permit forms&lt;/a&gt; shows that the city may not have been collecting all the information needed to quantify the housing stock. The forms for single-family homes and duplexes do provide part of the puzzle, because they ask builders what kind of structure was on the land before the construction, and what will be there after construction is finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/residential_permit_form.png&quot; alt=&quot;part of a residential building permit application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city uses the same form for building multifamily apartment buildings that it uses for nonresidential buildings. This form has a field for “# of units,” but it’s not always clear whether applicants interpreted that to mean the number of units where work will be performed, the number of units that will be added if the permit is granted, or just the total number of units in the building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/commercial_permit_form.png&quot; alt=&quot;part of a commercial building permit application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem is the separate form for demolition, which doesn’t specifically ask how many units are being eliminated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/demo_form.png&quot; alt=&quot;part of a demolition permit application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The table below shows some typical data collected from the city’s permit forms for activities at a single address, 2819 Rio Grande. In 2007, the dormitory that stood there was demolished and replaced with new student housing. The number of “HousingUnits” associated with the demolition is zero, even though it would be more useful to know how many old units were being eliminated. Then there are 85 housing units reported for the “Shell” work on the new building. After that, the builders apparently report the same 85 housing units in the “Finish Out” phase. For a researcher dealing with hundreds of thousands of permit records, it would be tough if not impossible to automate a count of changes in the housing supply based on this dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;post-table&quot;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Issued Date&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Permit Class&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Work Class&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Housing Units&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2007-05-03&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C- 649 Demolition All Other Bldgs Com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Demolition&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2819 RIO GRANDE ST&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;dEMO A DORMITORY&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2007-10-09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C- 321 Pkg Garage Bldg &amp;amp; Open Deck&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;New&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2819 RIO GRANDE ST garage&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;New construction 3 story parking 2 stories below grade 1 story grade&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2007-10-09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C- 105 Five or More Family Bldgs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shell&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2819 RIO GRANDE ST&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;New construction 5 story wood frame apartment over 3 story parking garage&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;85&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2007-10-09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-1001 Commercial Finish Out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Remodel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2819 RIO GRANDE ST&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tenant finish out for unit details 1st Floor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2007-10-09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-1001 Commercial Finish Out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Remodel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2819 RIO GRANDE ST&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tenant finish out for unit details 2nd Floor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2007-10-09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-1001 Commercial Finish Out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Remodel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2819 RIO GRANDE ST&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tenant finish out for unit details 3rd Floor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2007-10-09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-1001 Commercial Finish Out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Remodel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2819 RIO GRANDE ST&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tenant finish out for unit details 4th Floor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2007-10-09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-1001 Commercial Finish Out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Remodel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2819 RIO GRANDE ST&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tenant finish out for unit details 5th Floor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2007-10-09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-1001 Commercial Finish Out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Remodel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2819 RIO GRANDE ST&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tenant finish out for unit details 6th Floor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help advance the study of housing availability, Open Austin will make it a priority to convince the city to collect specific data from permit applicants about how many units are being added or removed from the housing supply, and to open up any other data the city has about housing supply from other sources. If you’re interested in improving the permit application process, also visit Open Austin’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/project-ideas/issues/68&quot;&gt;project to improve the city’s building permit website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/06/13/quantifying-austins-housing-supply</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/06/13/quantifying-austins-housing-supply</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finding a Story in Austin&#39;s Lobbying Data</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months, Open Austin members have tried a series of experiments with &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.austintexas.gov/dataset/Lobbyists/bqav-9x6a&quot;&gt;the city’s open lobbying data&lt;/a&gt; to find out how much it tells us about local politics. In one &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.open-austin.org/lobbying-in-austin/&quot;&gt;experimental chart&lt;/a&gt;, we graphed the running totals of lobbyists registered to work for various companies at any given time. On that graph, we can see when various companies hired lobbyists, but we don’t really know why the companies hired them or who the companies were trying to persuade. The reason lobbying data interests us is that it’s supposed to shine a light on how government decisions are made, but we really can’t make out much of a story in that graph. If we already knew the recent history of city politics, maybe we could guess the significance of the dates when AT&amp;amp;T or Uber decided to add a few more lobbyists to their payroll. But clearly, it would take a lot of research or deep expertise in the city’s political scene to put the existing data in context, and it’s not likely to be cost-efficient for anyone to research the story behind every filing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-solution&quot;&gt;The solution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Council Member &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mystatesman.com/news/news/local/austin-officials-to-create-new-lobbying-registrati/npmr3/&quot;&gt;Leslie Pool&lt;/a&gt; has offered a solution to this problem by introducing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lobbyreformnow.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/CityOrd-lobby-RR-June-6.pdf&quot;&gt;a new bill&lt;/a&gt; to improve the quality of data available about city lobbying. If it passes, the rules about disclosing lobbying at city hall will be about as strong as the equivalent rules for the state Legislature. One dogged proponent of lobbying reform is attorney &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityhall.blog.statesman.com/2015/08/25/how-one-attorney-made-fixing-austins-lobbying-law-his-personal-crusade/&quot;&gt;Fred Lewis&lt;/a&gt;, who highlights the benefits of reform through his organization, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lobbyreformnow.com/whats-happening/&quot;&gt;“Lobby Reform Now!”&lt;/a&gt;. Because current law has an ill-defined exception for lobbying “incidental” to one’s regular job, Lewis decries the existing law as “essentially voluntary and meaningless.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Importantly, the new bill will require electronic filing not just of registration forms, but also the lobbying activity forms. Its passage will mean that for the first time, the city will release open data about how much each client paid to each lobbyist, and about how much money each lobbyist spent on each city official. Also, lobbyists will have to report the subject matter of their lobbying and report the addresses of any locations where they’re seeking building permits. Releasing this data would be very helpful for city government transparency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For comparison, on the state level, it’s possible to link lobbyists’ expenditures to individuals, which at least lets us see communities among lawmakers and legislators. Here’s an image of which lobbyists paid for travel for state legislators from 2004 to 2014:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/TX_lobby_travel_filings_2004-2014.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/TX_lobby_travel_filings_2004-2014.svg&quot; alt=&quot;state legislator travel network graph&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even on the state level, it’s not easy to make the data tell a story. We can’t easily infer what the lobbyists are trying to accomplish when they buy lobbyists’ meals or pay for their travel. It’s too bad the graphs don’t show who each lobbyist spoke to on each client’s behalf, and which issues they discussed. Still, the more political data the government releases, the more opportunities it creates for useful insights. To learn more about our data exploration, visit Open Austin’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-austin/lobbying-in-austin&quot;&gt;Github repo for lobbyist data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-can-you-do&quot;&gt;What can you do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Austin City Council is set to vote on Council Member Pool’s lobby reform proposal on June 23rd. As the draft stands today, it would make Austin a model city in terms of reporting lobbyist activity. As it stands, the proposal has no problematic provisions but we expect lobbyists may try to put forth weakening admendments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please, between now and 6/23, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.austintexas.gov/email/all-council-members&quot;&gt;call or email the offices of the mayor and your council member&lt;/a&gt; to support the bill without amendments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/06/12/finding-a-story-in-austins-lobbying-data</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://open-austin.github.io//blog/2016/06/12/finding-a-story-in-austins-lobbying-data</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
